Such a boy!
Kazik. Kazik,
speak to me.
Let's get out of here!
Help...me.
No stinking Jews
in my line.
The bread is for those
on the Aryan side, not Jews.
Go to your side!
Go to the ghetto.
Officer, I'm a veteran of
the Polish armed services.
Then you are
a fighter, huh?
Uhh!
Mordechai Anielewicz,
you're wanted for work
detail. Let's go.
Work detail?
Where?
Who knows?
What's the difference?
Huh? All Jews
ordered to report.
Well, how will I know
what to wear?
Don't get smart.
Put on a shirt.
Let's get moving.
This work detail,
it wouldn't, by any chance,
be a German work detail.
I warned you.
I work for my people.
Now move!
Uhh!
You, a Jewish policeman,
are a traitor to your people.
For this alone,
I should kill you.
But, often I ask myself
the following:
Can a moral man--
that's me--
maintain his moral code
in an immoral world?
Does this question
interest you?
Get out of here,
before I hurt you.
Papa, why are so many
people moving here?
Just be glad you've
got the bread, Tosia.
Take off your hat.
No, thank you.
I said take off your hat.
Halt!
Hurry up!
What's the matter with you?
I take off my hat
for myself, Yitzhak,
for nobody else.
What now?
No!
Oh, please stop.
Stop.
Let go.
No.
Please! Please stop.
It's my grandson, David.
The bastards.
Creates a Jewish police force
to do their dirty work,
unless, they feel like having
a little fun themselves.
Of course,
divide and conquer.
Yeah.
What is next?
Kazik.
What are you doing
with this fancy car?
Driving, if you
hadn't noticed.
Did you steal it?
Now, Mordechai...
Why would I steal
what I can have for free?
What scheme
are you up to now?
I am the official driver
for Adam Czerniakow.
The head of
the Jewish council?
That's who I'm here to pick
up, traffic permitting.
Help us set up a meeting
with your boss Czerniakow.
If I did that, as his driver,
I'd put my position at risk.
If you don't, you'd be
helping the Germans.
This doesn't worry you,
aiding the enemy?
I would worry more
if I couldn't feed myself
and what remains of my family.
Never mind how we deal
with the Jewish police, huh?
with schooling the children.
We all have families--
Mordechai.
We don't want kazik
to lose his job.
Kazik.
I wish you well.
Mira's contacted some
sympathizers at the border,
who said they might get some
of our students out of Poland.
But it has to be
right away.
What do you think?
If you can get them out
of Poland and to Palestine,
then I would do it at once,
before the opportunity is lost.
Yeah.
I think you're right.
Wish me luck.
Luck.
Mordechai.
You are taking
these boys illegally.
All Jewish men
between the age of 12 to 60
are decreed to perform
forced labor.
Did you examine
their documents?
And you are?
Yitzhak Zuckerman,
their teacher.
Look at their documents.
These boys are legally
exempt from forced labor.
Yes, they are,
aren't they?
Ooh!
Today everyone works,
Zuckerman.
See that Zuckerman gets
the opportunity to work as well!
Uhh!
Hello, everyone.
Hello, everybody.
All take your seats, please.
Mordechai.
Yes, Julian.
I understand--
we understand
we might be leaving...
For Palestine,
through Romania, any day now.
What do you know about this?
Where did you hear this?
Rumor.
Rumor from where?
Rumor mill.
Uh, well, unfortunately, I have
to leave immediately today.
But I hope to return very soon
and address this naughty rumor.
In the meantime, taking my
place for today's lesson,
I have a very
special treat--
a renowned scholar
and rumormonger,
Mr. Julian Wald.
Julian, come
up here, please.
Ok, who remembers
today's topic?
Anybody?
Help me out here, because, uh,
I forgot to write it down.
Something
about morality?
Yes, Frania.
Can a moral man maintain his
moral code in an immoral world?
Very good. Ok, Julian?
You can work with that topic?
Uh, sure.
Good.
Ok. Today's topic--
can an immoral man
maintain his moral code...
On a first date?
So, everything is arranged
until you get to the border.
Mira...
But still...You'll have
to get across on your own.
Mm-hmm. And?
And if you find
a safe passage...
Yes?
If you find a safe passage
and return safely,
then you will
get a reward.
What kind of a reward?
Well, perhaps
the fulfillment
of your dreams.
Seeing your students
make the desert bloom
and become fertile.
That's it?
It's a lot of work. I mean,
you know. The danger alone is...
All right. Well, perhaps
the eternal gratitude
of your people
and of, uh,
a certain person
in particular.
Who?
Someone very close
to you.
What kind of gratitude?
What if I find
2 safe passages?
You can take off
your armband now.
Go.
Get down to the stream
and follow it.
Over there
is the border.
Is it very far?
No. You should reach a safe
house before nightfall.
They are aware
of your journey.
I will receive
my payment now.
Thank you very much.
Good luck to you.
Welcome to our country!
See if you can pull
around them.
Well, kazik, how did you get
this assignment driving my car?
Your other driver was taken
to a slave labor battalion.
And?
And, uh...
I was chosen to replace him.
Kazik...
Yes, sir.
Do not...
Steal the car.
Yes, sir.
Czerniakow, a detachment
of SS soldiers
under the command
of lieutenant Mueller
expended a number of hours
burning the Jewish
synagogue on Staffki street
upon request of
the health ministry
after finding
unsanitary conditions.
But the hostages
taken to Pawiak...
We provided you with
the paperwork yesterday.
For this operation, 30 liters
of benzene were expended,
for which we will expect
reimbursement.
For the Jewish council, there
will be 20 zlotys per liter--
600 zlotys.
We will get you
the funds.
About the other matter,
23 hostages were taken--
some--some women
and children--
all because a Polish police
officer was roughed up.
Certainly, the children--
this paperwork--
ah, yeah, here it is.
Commissar Auerswald...
You have appointed me to
administer to the needs
of 350,000 people.
I find it impossible
to manage the community
under these circumstances,
and I must ask you
to release me
from my position
as the head
of the Jewish council.
That would be inadvisable.
The fine levied on each
prisoner is 10,000 zlotys.
So if the Jewish council
wishes to pay the full fine--
230,000 zlotys--
make sure they do so
by 6 P.M. tomorrow.
So...heh heh.
You should get busy...
Czerniakow.
Stop!
What are you
hiding there?
Ah...
Smells good.
It'd be better with jam,
but...Try it.
Get out of here.
Oh, please, it's for my father.
He's very sick, needs it badly.
How badly?
Please.
Aah!
Tosia.
Now...get out of here.
Tosia, come.
Ahh!
Are you all right,
mama?
Oh, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
It's too dangerous
to go out like you do.
Hello, dear.
Come, Rachel.
Papa.
Go.
We're going to sell
a few books.
I'm trying to keep
your favorites.
I think we need some more.
Do you want another blanket?
Are you warm enough?
I won't allow you.
Do you hear me?
Papa, I'm going to keep
your favorites.
And I'll bring back
bread.
Your mother thinks I
don't know she's sewing
for the rich Polish
women, but I do.
Make sure she's careful
on the streets.
So dangerous.
Promise me you won't
tell her I know.
I promise.
We have
to hurry, Rachel.
I promise, papa.
I got the hat.
Be careful on
the other side.
I will be, papa.
I will.
Now light
the shabbos candles.
Boruch ata adonai
eloheinu melech haolam...
Sorry I'm late.
You heard about
the ransom demand?
Yes. It's a terrible
situation.
I think now we must
ask your men to speak
with the relatives
of the hostages,
see what
they can contribute.
How much time do we have?
Tomorrow night,
6:00.
For 38 years,
this is on my hand.
Here.
Put it in the envelope,
Mrs. Rochon.
I will get my David back?
He's a good boy.
They have no business
taking him.
You are a good boy, too.
Your mother must be
very proud, Calel.
Good day.
Captain Szerynski, this is
the ring you wanted to see.
Hey!
What--
what's a pretty girl
like you doing here?
Same thing you're doing--
getting by.
Ha ha. But you're
not Jewish.
So why are you
in the ghetto?
But...I am.
I have to go
to the other side
to make money
for food.
Can you help me
get across?
I could.
But then I could cause myself
a lot of trouble.
This is the money from
captain Szerynski's men.
And this is
all you received?
Yes.
You counted it twice?
No.
3 times.
They're short.
I know.
They're 80,000 zlotys short.
I know!
Already 4:00.
Why didn't Szerynski call?
He said
he's doing his best.
Get me rabbi Lebowicz.
Come, rabbi, please.
Excuse me for
being so bold, sir,
but a rabbi should not go
into an establishment
of such ill repute.
Kazik.
In the Jewish faith,
it is customary that we
demonstrate our love of god
through our good deeds.
It is true.
And in this manner,
god is able to bestow his
great blessings upon us.
It is also true.
I believe today
you have a special duty
to demonstrate
your love of god.
Should you wish to do so,
preferably before 6 P.M...
Mr. Czerniakow...
I wish to thank you for
affording me this...
Special opportunity to
receive god's blessing.
Should you ever bring
your rabbi in my club again,
if you burst in
like this again,
I will kill you.
Make no mistake
about it.
Commissar Auerswald!
Commissar--
commissar Auerswald is
not here.
He must be here. He's
handling the Pawiak hostages.
There's a deadline, 6:00.
Commissar Auerswald
was called to Berlin
for important meetings.
Then who is in charge?
Please, do not stand
so close to my desk.
Who is in char--
I'm asking you...
Who--who is in charge?
I'm here to pay the full fine.
There is a deadline.
I know nothing about
this situation.
The commissar left no
instructions about this.
Someone must know.
Who is handling this?
Step back from the desk!
I do not wish
your diseases.
This is the payment.
Call Pawiak prison.
Tell them the payment
has been delivered.
Did you say Pawiak?
Pawiak prison, yes.
23 hostages.
I saw a notice
on Pawiak.
Yes, here it is.
"On the authority
of the commissar's office,
"23 prisoners were...
"Executed
at 10:00 this morning
for crimes against
the Polish people."
No.
N...
Th-these were not crimes.
There were no crimes.
These were innocent people!
They were children.
You are with child.
Did you know
they were children?
I know nothing about
this situation.
If you wish to discuss
this with the commissar,
he will return
next Tuesday.
You are with child.
Have you no connection?
I have answered
your questions.
You are free to go now.
This morning, at 10:00,
the 23 hostages...
Were executed...
By order of
the commissar's office.
I am very sorry.
Uhh!
So you still don't want to
tell me who your comrades are?
Huh?!
Maybe I can be
more convincing.
Very convincing.
We've had 4,000 deaths
by starvation and typhus.
The population is now
approaching 450--
the Germans are now
rationing daily calories.
We're calculating
2,613 for German nationals,
699 for poles,
and 184 for Jews.
Auerswald's office has
ordered the Jewish council
to pay for all costs,
labor, and material
for this ghetto war.
I--I--I want you all
to know
that I do not believe
that our situation...
I do not believe it
to be hopeless.
I believe that
if we remain strong...
And active...
That somehow, some...
Sense of reason...
Will return. It's...
We--we must persevere.
Hey.
Wait. Wait!
Let me see what's
in your coat!
I don't have any bread.
I can see it.
I don't have anything.
Leave me alone.
I have money.
No!
First you give me
the bread.
Mira.
I can't believe
you're alive.
It's been so long.
Are you ok?
Yes. I'm fine.
Ooh. You're hur--
I'll take this.
How's my sister?
Gina's fine.
Do you want me
to wake her?
No, no, no.
Let her sleep.
Ooh. Are you sure
you don't need a doctor?
No, no. I just, uh,
I just need to rest.
Whew...
You weren't successful,
were you?
No.
Well, if we can't get to
Palestine and be farmers,
we'll stay here
and be fighters.
That's a fine way
to greet a friend.
I wouldn't do
that again.
Somebody else would shoot first
and ask questions later.
Duly noted.
So, kazik, what
could have made you
give up your fancy car
and join the resistance?
I can't think of a better
way to meet women.
Always the idealist, huh?
Ah, Yitzhak.
You look like crap.
Thank you.
But to be honest,
you were never really that
good-looking to begin with.
Thank you.
Don't worry.
You'll survive.
Yitzhak, I brought you
a little something.
A gift from my travels.
The first of many, I hope.
Here.
In case you run into
trouble again.
You and me, we're going
to put a stop to this, yes?
We've already begun to bring
together various factions
into a coherent
underground organization.
And the bund?
Are they with us?
They're still
unconvinced.
We have so much to do
and little time to do it in.
We've organized our own
underground soup kitchens,
our own schools,
our own hospitals.
It's our own
little society.
We're just surrounded
by a brick wall.
What about the...
No. I've been unable to get you
a meeting with Czerniakow.
He refuses.
He refuses?
I don't see him, do you?
His car is there.
There with captain Szerynski
and that pest Calel Wasser.
He'll be here.
There he is.
Sir.
So you refuse
to meet my friend.
So, tell me,
my recently departed driver,
with whom am I
refusing to meet?
Mordechai Anielewicz.
Oh, professor Ringelblum's
friend
who has an interesting
history.
Yeah. And an interest
in protecting our people.
And you think that
by lighting up flares
and having underground
meetings
and preparing resistance
against the Germans,
we'll accomplish this?
It's not what
I propose, sir.
We must strike back
in any way we can.
You're not worried
about the German doctrine
of collective responsibility?
Because what you are proposing
is spitting right in their eye,
and they will retaliate
against innocent Jews,
even harder than they did
in the last hostage crisis.
They suffer anyway.
Every day, they die of
disease and starvation,
and worse, and you sit
at the table,
you negotiate with these Germans
as if they're reasonable?
Yes, I do. I try to
minimize the harm.
Believe it or not,
so do we.
Please,
give us a chance.
Give us money and your
support to get started.
Your dream is a--
it's a romantic notion
that will get you all killed.
And I will not support it.
I will not.
And--and you should be
wearing a hat.
In this weather,
you can get pneumonia.
Good day.
And 5...
6...
7...
8...
Plie ...
And stretch...
5...6...
7...8...
1...2...3...4...
They're gone.
It's clear.
So you talked
to Czerniakow?
What did he say?
He said he won't
support us right now.
So what about later?
We're going to be
more persuasive.
Perhaps we can rendezvous
at the Copernicus statue tonight
and discuss your
views more fully.
There are many things that
we must talk about today.
It is our priority to find
more women couriers
who can pass as gentiles
and work on the Aryan side.
Why not men
who can pass?
Clara.
Men do not fare as well
in a strip search.
Circumcision.
Papa?
I know you will think
it's dangerous,
but I have some
fresh bread for you.
Papa?
Papa! Papa!
I have bread for you!
Fresh bread.
Papa.
Papa!
Amen.
* 1, 2, 3
So, you're ok here?
Yes.
'Cause you can stay
with me. You know this.
It's fine with me.
You feel safer here,
don't you?
Yes.
It's true I'm afraid.
And if you were to be taken,
I would be alone.
You've been thinking
about this.
Go to class.
Go.
* 1, 2, 3
Dr. Korczak.
Uh, you have any luck convincing
Czerniakow to help us?
No.
But come to our next
recital.
Yes. Jonah's
on Thursday.
Czerniakow
loves recitals.
Ah, ah, very good.
Tosia,
is this the child?
Yes.
You found her
near the cemetery?
That's correct.
And you lack the resources
to care for her?
I have nothing.
Hmm. This child
is not well.
Mrs. Linder, can we afford
to take another child?
We cannot.
We cannot take
another child.
But then,
we have no choice,
do we?
I want you
to meet my family.
Yes, sir.
My wife else.
Pleasure.
This is Calel Wasser, one of
out finest young officers.
And this is
our daughter Inka.
We'll let you two
get acquainted.
It's a lovely house.
Thank you.
That ring...
Couldn't help but notice,
it's very unique.
Yes.
Have you had it long?
No.
Just since
my birthday.
And your father,
he gave it to you?
Yes.
How did you know?
Just a guess.
Uh...we just had reports...
That there were mass killings
in the village
where your parents live.
No one survived.
How about the rumor
that the gestapo
has offered you
a certificate to Palestine?
It is not a rumor.
It is the truth.
I refused.
I must thank you for the help
raising money for us.
I wish I could do more
for the children.
Well, then, by all means...
Do more.
Do not lose your temper.
Let me do the talking, ok?
You do
the talking.
Mr. chairman.
You have received
our latest request?
Yes, I have received it.
You want to buy arms.
And the council...
They're aware.
And?
You want to buy guns.
And then what?
Jewish honor.
A father who is hiding
his son is not honorable.
A rabbi who is teaching
a child his lessons
is not honorable.
A mother who is taking care
of her children, and many more,
she is not honorable either.
No. For you...
Honor--honor can only come
out of the barrel of a gun.
You talk about Jewish honor.
I talk about
Jewish responsibility.
Call it what you like.
Will the council support
the resistance movement?
Oh, no, no.
They will oppose it,
it's for your own good.
What?! You've heard of
the mass killings, yes?
These are not rumors.
These are facts from the
mouths of our own people.
Outside of Chelmno,
thousands of Jews
were taken in sealed vans
with hoses pumping gas in.
I know this because
my parents were among them.
I'm sorry for your loss.
The largest armies
in the world
have not been able
to defeat the Nazis.
What makes you think that
a handful of untrained
Jewish citizens with pistols
will be the ones to prevail.
So instead of opposing
the Germans,
you propose to leave the fate of
our people in their very hands.
If you'll excuse me.
Mothers held their children
to their breasts
to protect them
from the gas.
When the Germans found
these babies still alive,
they would swing them
against trees to kill them.
Is that graphic
enough for you?
That's not the point.
That is the point.
Let's just salute,
huh?
Salute...
Salute what?
Your disciples, your followers,
your foot soldiers.
My what?
The one over there...
In the parade.
That's your honor...
Chairman.
Out!
It is an illegal gathering.
You are instructed
to return to your homes--
immediately.
Is this really necessary?
I struggle to find why
our recital
is injurious to
the third Reich.
I believe that
concludes today's program.
Please join us tomorrow
for a very special salute
to Richard Wagner.
Good evening.
Jew!
Play something for us.
We have just been
instructed to go home.
I instruct you now.
Play something.
Aah! Aah!
You...
Play something.
Kazik, grab the guns.
I'm sorry about your friend.
What do you
think you were doing?
I was avenging
a murder.
But the Germans
will retaliate.
They do whatever
they want to, anyway.
This is not a responsible
fighting organization.
Then we're not a responsible
No, you! You must not
act impulsively.
We must carefully plan
and coordinate every act--
I am tired, Yitzhak,
and I'm sick of it.
Of watching and waiting and
standing by and being passive.
I won't do it anymore.
We're not passive!
Prudent in our actions.
You need to get weapons from
the Polish underground.
Arie needs all the help
he can get.
You will look after
my sister?
I will.
Go.
5, 6, 7, 8--
What is this?
Ah.
You are Czerniakow,
chairman of the Jewish council?
Yes.
Yes, I'm Dr. Fritz Hippler
with the public information
office. Please, please.
Under the auspices
of secretary Goebbels
we are documenting
Jewish life in the ghetto,
and we wish you to be
a participant.
What do you
wish me to do?
Sit at your desk and conduct
your business as you would.
Come over here, please.
What is this?
This makes
the picture look good.
I would not have that.
Good. Now,
I want you people to...
Talk and conduct business
as you would
on any normal day.
Please, have a seat.
Are we ready? Yeah?
And roll camera, and...
Begin.
Begin talking.
Ahem.
Yes, Nathan?
Are you aware that
there is a rather large
candelabra on your desk?
Yes, I know that.
Keep talking.
And are you aware that wax
is dripping all over your work?
Yes, I see that.
If I may ask, why would you have
a large candelabra on your desk
if it drips wax
all over your work?
They have it, Nathan,
because it is good
for the picture.
Stop.
Stop, stop, stop, stop. Stop.
Just a moment, please.
Uh, the lighting
is all wrong.
Look,
this one has a perfectly good
Hebrew nose, and I can't see it.
Commissar Auerswald, there's
talk about deportations and, uh,
putting to death
of people in the camps.
Just talk.
Uh-huh.
Rumors.
I can assure you,
no truth to them
whatsoever.
Mm-hmm.
Places, people.
Please.
Good, and would you
sit down, please.
In your chair.
Could we see that?
Yes, that's much better.
Uh, there is--there is
one thing, though.
Um...
You're all being
very still.
Uh, too still.
Jewish people normally move
their hands when they talk,
so I want to see you move
your hands more, yes?
Let me see that.
Like this. Bigger.
And you...
Very good.
Yes, that's...
Something like that, yes.
Good. All right.
And roll camera...
And begin talking,
and use your hands.
Adam.
What?
Are you aware that there's
a large candelabra
in the middle
of your desk?
Yes, Nathan.
You can rest assured
that I am fully aware
of all
that is transpiring.
The essential
trait of the Jew
is that he always tries
to hide his origin
when among non-Jews.
People, I want you
to work faster.
Wherever rats turn up.
They carry destruction
to the land
in spreading
diseases and plagues,
just as the Jews do
among mankind.
This is a conspiracy
against all non-Jews
by a sick, deceitful,
poisoned race
against the Aryan peoples
and their moral laws.
Thank you,
Marek.
Enjoy your work,
but do it faster.
Remember, work...
Will make you free.
Come on, Sarah.
I have for you
2 work permits, all right?
Listen to me.
The cards right here--
they will save your life.
All Jews,
regardless of sex and age,
with certain exceptions,
are to be deported to work
camps in the east, by 4 P.M.
Commissar Auerswald.
Today we expect you to provide
the first contingent
of 6,000 people.
This will be
the minimum daily quota.
And--and the children
in orphanages?
Regardless
of sex and age.
Uh, perhaps--
regardless
of sex and age.
Lieutenant,
I am Adam Czerniakow.
I'm the chairman
of the Jewish council.
I have been given assurances
at the highest level
concerning the treatment
of the children.
I fully expect those
assurances to be honored.
Kindly sign
this proclamation.
I will not.
Mr. Czerniakow,
if the deportation
is impeded in any way
by you or your people,
the consequences
will be dire.
This is the beginning
of an assault
on the existence
of the Jewish people.
So what do we do in
the face of this horror?
Do we--do we sit
on our hands and, uh,
wait for the next slap
in the face of the enemy...
Or do we hide
within ourselves,
so that the blows
don't hurt us so much?
Or maybe we--we lift
our hands to god, huh,
and pray for
the Messiah to come?
Huh? Messiah,
are you coming?
I--I don't think he's coming,
so what do we do?
We use our hands
and our arms
and our hearts
and our lives and our deaths
and we fight back. We resist.
If you can't fight, then run.
You can't run, then hide,
but you must resist...
Tosia!
You must.
Rachel!
Mama!
Tosia!
Mama, show them
the permit!
Tosia!
Show them!
I didn't bring it! Aah!
No!
Tosia!
Mama!
Aah! I want
to go with you!
Ah! Mama!
I want
to go with you!
Mama!
Those who are willing
to resist must work together.
We must share arms.
We must share information.
Mordechai.
What?
You must leave for Warsaw.
What is it?
We must leave...Now.
"They have asked me
to kill the children
"with my own hands.
This I cannot do.
Signed,
Adam Czerniakow."
Don't forget
your diaries.
There will be plenty of time
to record your thoughts.
You said we had
15 minutes.
Out!
And we will
take our 15 minutes.
And when
we get to the camp,
we will all get to see
the most beautiful pine
trees and birch trees,
and if there
are beautiful trees,
what else will we see?
Birds.
Birds, yes.
That's right. That's
right, but what else?
Rabbits?
Yes, yes. Very good.
Very good, yes. And?
Squirrels.
Very good, Jan.
Many,
many squirrels.
Uh, and don't
forget the flag.
* almost ready
* there will be many
adventures here *
* 1, 2, 3
* the children
are smiling... *
* 1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3 *
* forward walk,
forward bravely *
don't let them know
that you are afraid.
Don't let them know.
* 1, 2, 3
* the children are marching
down the street *
* 1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3 *
do your friends in the bund
still have contact
with the railway
workers?
Yes.
Can you make it out
of the ghetto again?
I can try.
Go, Zygmunt.
Follow the trains,
and tell us definitively
where they are going.
* 1, 2, 3
* above the road,
the sun is shining *
* smiling
at the children *
* 1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3 *
* forward walk,
forward bravely *
* there will be many
adventures here *
* 1, 2, 3
Sir, please. I am separated
from my wife and children.
Can I have a minute to find them
and board the train together?
On the train.
No, no, sir,
please. Please.
Take these.
They are worth a lot. Just give
me a minute. Please, I beg you.
On the train!
* 1, 2, 3
* the children are marching
down the road *
* 1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3 *
* above the road
the sun is shining *
* smiling at
the children *
* 1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3 *
* all on board,
all are ready *
* there will be many
adventures here *
* 1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3 *
* the children are marching
down the road *
* 1, 2, 3,
1, 2, 3 *
* above the road
the sun is shining *
* smiling
at the children... *
Dr. Korczak,
why are you here?
You're exempt
from this order.
What about
the children?
The children must
board the train.
Then I will do as well.
You must not do this.
I won't allow you
on the train.
Well, then kill me here and now
in front of the children.
Don't lemme go!
Lemme stay with you!
I'll be safe! Don't lemme
go with my parents!
Please! I'll be safe with you.
Don't let them take me--
get off!
Don't let them
take me away!
What is it?
Where are we going?
Marek said
they want workers...
But they're not
taking cripples.
It's your only chance.
Nurse!
Quickly, now, quickly,
before the guards return!
Ok, it's your
only chance.
Oh, but I'm
a dancer.
Clara,
hold your breath.
Gina was taken
to the camps.
Zygmunt is back
from Treblinka.
Zygmunt.
It's Mordechai. Can you
tell us what you saw?
Zygmunt.
Collect yourself
and tell us.
Children, women,
by the thousands,
gassed to death
in showers.
They can hide
everything,
but not the stench
of the dead.
This is the map
of the camp of death.
of Treblinka.
And the people
pleading for their lives
with this scum.
This scum--I want
their blood on my hands.
We know that
Adam Czerniakow
has committed suicide.
We now know that
300,000 Warsaw Jews
have been either sent
to Treblinka, a death camp,
or have simply
been murdered.
For now, the deportations
have ceased.
They're going to resume, when
they do, we'll no longer submit.
We are going to respond
with armed resistance.
We have to use
this time wisely
to root out traitors
and collaborators,
to acquire weapons,
to prepare a plan of battle,
most importantly, to let all
those who remain in the ghetto
know that we can and we will
fight our enemy now
with all the Jewish groups
finally under one banner
with one purpose.
Perhaps we can save some lives
and remove a few Germans
from the face of the earth.
But this much,
this much I promise you.
We will live with honor...
And we will die with honor.
Jewish honor.
I'm--I'm ashamed
of...
Of what
I've been party to.
I'm a lawyer
by training.
I just wanted to save my family,
to survive like everyone else.
Now, I'm...
I'm ashamed
to wear my uniform.
You should be ashamed.
Stop it. Stop crying
like a child.
I don't trust him.
Send him on a mission.
Send him on a mission,
and then we'll see
which side he's on.
Zachariah
will observe him.
If he fails,
we'll execute him,
like the others
who have been
exceptionally cruel
to their own people.
If he succeeds,
keep him in uniform.
It could prove useful to have a
policeman working for us.
We want you to go undercover
to the Aryan side
to smuggle weapons
into the ghetto.
Are you willing
to do that?
Yes.
Good.
She has no family anymore.
There's no one left.
This is a map
of Treblinka.
Get it to one of our couriers,
and it must travel to England.
Do you
see your name?
Viescha.
Viescha Sovitska.
You are to hide this map
inside your shoe.
Do you understand?
Do you know
what night this is?
No.
I think it might be
Friday night.
We didn't light
the sabbath candles.
I don't have any
sabbath candles.
Good night.
I forgot
to ask your name.
It's viescha.
And you are?
Frania.
Good night,
frania.
Boruch ata adonai...
Eloheinu melech haolam...
Asher kideshanu
b'mitzvotav...
V'etzivanu...
L'hadlikner...
Shel shabbat.
I say that we just go out
in broad daylight
and we shoot
as many as we can.
Forget dying in a Blaze
of glory, Mira.
Why give them the satisfaction
and make it easy on them?
I still think we should
wait as long as possible
so we can acquire more
weapons and train.
No, Yitzhak.
What we have to do
is we've to organize
escape to the woods.
Create a larger organization and
fight from outside the ghetto.
No, no, no. We'll never
make it on the outside.
We'll be sold out.
We'll be informed on.
We'll be slaughtered.
I think we should
take them all hostage
and make them listen to German
folk music, really loud,
until they lose their minds
and they give up.
This is serious.
Every day of peace
in the ghetto
is another day
that we can prepare
for the organized attack
of the future.
We need to send a series of
messages to the Jewish police,
to the Jewish council,
to our own people
in the ghetto,
to the Nazis, and we need
to do it now, Yitzhak.
We can't wait.
They've to know who we are
and we mean business,
even if it means
using up, uh...
All the weapons.
Yes, even if
it means this.
Then we just
have to pray.
For what?
For what? For tosia to get
the map out of the ghetto,
and for she and arie to smuggle
more weapons back in.
Unh! Oh!
Hey! Hey!
Go in the shack.
Come on.
Place of work?
Schmidt foundry.
Location?
Chmielna 2.
Give me your coat
and dress.
Now the rest.
You want this, too?
Shoes.
I said shoes.
Do you want me
to use this?
Another one.
Another one!
A Jew has escaped!
We must capture
him now! Quickly!
Get dressed. Get out
of here. Quickly.
Hey! Where are
you going?
To work. I just
passed my inspection.
Hey, Jew, what
are you selling today?
How close are we
to the plant?
A couple of blocks.
You're lucky.
Lucky?
Most people that go
to that guard shack
don't come out.
I think this is where
you take your
armband off and leave us.
Are you going
to turn me in?
No.
Viescha.
Viescha, it's kazik.
I couldn't get close
to the gate.
It wasn't safe.
So I had to follow
the wagon. Come, walk.
Walk. It's all right.
Blackmailers up ahead.
We need to laugh.
Laugh?
Yes. Jews look down.
Jews look sad.
Jews avert their eyes.
Blackmailers
can smell fear,
so, can you laugh?
Try again.
Try to do it big
like this.
I said sleep,
not sheep.
Sleep.
Not bad.
Keep practicing.
Viescha, this
is Michael Klepflisch.
Hi.
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Arie Wilmer.
We've met.
Get to know
them both well.
So, he was good.
I wanted
to arrange a meeting
with your boss,
Szerynsky.
You can accomplish this?
Yes.
Good.
I'm sorry if it's...
It's been in my shoe
for a couple days.
No. It gives it
character.
Do you realize that
this map of Treblinka
will travel
by special courier
all the way to the prime
minister Churchill himself?
With the other documents
he will carry,
hopefully, it will
persuade the allies
to give us
the weapons we need
to bomb the German trains
and hopefully even
the death camps themselves.
Do you understand now?
Yes.
Come on, Zach!
Zygmunt, let's go!
Captain Szerynski?
I have a message for you
from the Jewish
fighting organization.
For your traitorous
activities
and for collaboration
with the enemy,
you have been tried
in a court of your people
and have been
condemned to death.
Good-bye.
Good-bye?
Aah!
Is it too heavy?
It's all right.
I can carry it,
but what if it
gets dropped?
You wouldn't want
to drop dynamite.
No, but what
if something falls?
You wouldn't want
something to fall.
It could get bumped.
Bumped could be ok.
Good work.
Good shooting.
Good job, Calel.
Calel,
welcome.
Welcome to the family,
Calel.
Now the Germans
will come to us, yeah?
Hey, lady, wait.
Hold on.
Thank you.
Let's go quickly,
lady.
Steady...
Aim...
Fire!
Good, good.
Remember,
one round,
one German.
No wasted
rounds, yeah?
Ok. Front row
kneels.
All right.
Steady...
Tosia.
Viescha.
It's all right.
You're
with friends here.
Thanks.
Steady,
aim, fire!
Good, and steady...
Mordechai.
Yeah?
Tosia's brought
some gifts.
Ah, perfect timing.
Good. When can we
expect more?
Arie said there will be
another shipment
momentarily.
He will smuggle them
personally.
Good. Good.
Steady...
Aim, fire!
Devorah, I said aim.
Yes, very important
to aim.
Arguably almost as
important as firing itself.
Shira, see if you can
help Devorah to aim.
Frania.
Marek.
Oh!
Look what tosia's
brought us.
Zivia, please,
a good rule of thumb--
never to pat
the bomb-maker on the back
while he's working. Ok?
Ah, what's this?
Ohh!
Dynamite.
Excellent.
I also need--
Potassium chloride.
Bottles.
Can you get me those?
Yes, I'll try.
I also need a new
set of lungs.
Marek used to work
in the lab
at the hospital.
This is more fun.
Uhh, anything else,
Mr. engineer?
More.
Just more
of everything.
More.
You all are
under arrest!
Put down your bombs
and return immediately
to the umschlagplatz!
Heil Hitler!
So that would bring us
here, right?
Kazik.
Who's that girl
with the pistol?
That's Devorah Baron.
She's with Marek and Gutman,
at the brushmaker's.
That is
such a coincidence.
I was thinking that
I should be stationed
at the brushmaker's.
Don't you agree, boss?
Heil Hitler!
Intelligence estimates
that there are only
30 to 40,000 left,
Reichsfuhrer Himmler.
I'm disappointed,
colonel Von Sammern.
There are so many!
They sabotaged
our factories.
They attacked
our soldiers.
There.
And there.
Look. See?
And another.
Don't we have an understanding,
colonel Von Sammern,
that I can rely on you
to make sure that Warsaw's
free of these vermin?
Absolutely.
Into the blockade.
We are surrounded.
Mordechai! Mordechai!
Into the blockade.
We are surrounded.
All right, all right.
Let's go. Let's go!
Guns up here!
Do it. Do it!
Marek!
Don't forget the ammo.
Go with kazik!
Clara, let's go.
Clara, come on!
Get in line!
Get in the line,
I said!
Look straight!
Up here!
There are Jews inside!
Wo sind sie?
They're inside.
Here!
Aus!
Look out! Move!
Look out!
Look out! Look out!
Aah!
Come on!
Come and get me!
Come on.
Get out of here!
Yitzhak!
Come on.
It's enough! Let's go!
No!
Let's go!
Now!
We will fight
later!
Come on! Now!
Yitzhak, he's dead.
Come!
Please!
Get him off.
Enough!
All right.
Let's go.
Grab the guns
and ammunition.
Hurry!
Grab the guns!
For the first time,
we have stopped
the deportations.
For the first time,
the enemy knows
who we are, as a people.
They know that
we will resist.
we will fight back.
They know that
they're going to pay
for their mass murder.
What they don't know
is how long
and how hard
and how successfully
we are going to battle.
In fact, we are going to
light a torch of resistance,
and it's going to burn
so brightly
that others everywhere
are going to be inspired
to resist as well.
For Stosh, for Michael,
for Leon, for Ariel,
for Zvi...
And for Clara,
who sacrificed
their lives
for our dignity,
a moment, please,
of reflection
and of silence.
I have good news
to report.
Faced with ferocious
Jewish resistance,
the Germans
have surrendered.
Hitler has
apologized
for all
the inconvenience.
The Jews have won.
I should notify
the allies.
What for?
What have they
done for us?
My favorite thing
about the zoo
is the animals.
They're not going
to turn you in.
What about telling
that Polish monkey
over there?
Oh, no. He's ok.
He used to date
my cousin Ida.
This letter goes
to Klepflisch
as soon as you leave.
Follow my lead.
Sorry.
I was...
Just being protective.
Arie...
If you'd like to be
my boyfriend,
that's all right
with me.
You know I'll be
going on these missions,
and if I don't
come back,
I'd like somebody to know
that I didn't come back.
Stop!
Sir, this man died
on the Aryan side.
I have orders to take him
to the Jewish cemetery.
What's in the box?
A Jew named Izzy.
Open it.
The casket?
Open it now!
All right, sir.
Unh!
Get that thing
away from here!
Yes, sir.
Good work, Izzy.
You really are
a very good stinker.
Did arie say anything?
He said there were
more on the way.
But for now,
50 pistols
and 2 rifles.
But now I must attempt
an even more important
mission.
Procreation.
So that the fuhrer
has one more
ghetto fighter
to deal with.
Attempt is the right word.
My father-in-law,
he said,
"study hard.
Get a degree,
so you won't have
to dig ditches."
The home army is
very impressed
with our actions.
It's just a start.
I hope.
Throw it quickly!
Quickly!
Ohh!
Aah!
Look! Look, you both
want to stay and fight,
fine.
But what are you
going to fight with?
One of you must go.
Arie's sources are
probably in hiding,
terrified he might talk.
Arie won't talk.
Arie will not talk.
He won't talk, zivia.
We know that.
They don't.
Kazik, can we get him out?
It's difficult.
Can we do it?
How much will it cost?
It's not a
matter of money.
You must focus
on reconnecting
with arie's sources.
Now, come on.
Decide.
You know the Aryan culture.
You were raised--
you look more Aryan
and I know too many
people there.
I'm sure to be
recognized.
You know the language.
My language
is obviously foreign.
What if someone asks
where I'm from?
What if somebody
denounces me?
Flip a coin to decide?!
Come on, Yitzhak.
You go and you bring us back
the weapons that we need.
Look at this.
You look fine.
You look like
a Polish businessman.
Here.
If anybody asks you,
you came to town
to buy shirts. Ok?
The guards have been
greased.You're all set.
Look it--
look. This suit.
What do you want?
It's all we could find.
It's ridiculous!
You look fine.
Really.
Nice ankles.
Look. Ahem.
Your documents,
your new identity,
Vitok Metan.
Good luck, Marek.
Vitok.
Frania will escort
you to the other side.
She'll bring you
to tosia,
who'll arrange
for you to contact
all the necessary
poles. Ok?
Where's frania?
She's over there
with Julian.
She's one of our
very best.
Good.
I'll be watching
your back.
Oh, that makes me feel
much better.
Well...
I'm just
across the street.
Luck.
How is he?
He's not going to win
any beauty contests.
Welcome back.
You all right?
I've been better.
Conserve
your strength, ok?
Just rest.
Mordechai--
you'll fight later.
Just get better.
Uh...
Arie, I need
to ask you.
I didn't tell them
anything.
Rest.
Kazik, how did you
get him out?
We did nothing.
The gestapo
made a mistake
and accepted
our bribe.
Even when I believe
you're telling the truth,
I think you're
making it up.
Now, there's a vote
of confidence for you.
1929 lafite Rothschild.
Flawless. A bouquet
that will last a century.
Have yourself serve a sip,
Dr. Fritz hippler.
You won't regret it.
Do I lie?
Is it not flawless?
Yes, it's very good.
Good?
It's not good.
This is exquisite.
I liked your movie,
the eternal Jew.
It was relentless.
As the French would say,
apitoyer, without pity.
The eternal Jew.
What a terrifying title.
Hmm.
Big nose.
Fruity.
What do you think?
I agree.
You are not a wine
aficionado, are you?
No. Not really.
It's a Jewish wine,
made by Jews,
Willen Gott.
Rothschild.
Surprising, isn't it?
Hmm?
Enough about wine.
In confidence...
You've spent time around
colonel Von Sammern.
Haven't you?
Ja.
Tell me about him.
Where should I start?
With the engagement
on January 18,
when his troops were
first fired upon
by the sub-humans
of the Jewish sector.
German soldiers are massing
outside the ghetto
by the hundreds.
Caliber?
9-mm.
Ahh...
One German,
2 Germans,
3 Germans.
Tuvia,
caliber?
7.62.
7.92, carbine.
Julian, how did you
get the rifle?
My eyesight.
Julian.
I don't miss.
One German platoon.
Zygmunt.
7.92.
Everyone's in place.
Do you hear this?
They're singing.
The bastards
are singing.
Go. Go down.
Isaac, Sarah, move.
Auschwitz!
Treblinka!
Dachau!
Good shot, Julian!
Treblinka!
Bring down
Dr. hippler here.
Hit the tank!
Hit the tank
while the hatch is open!
Why are you filming?
I was assigned
by Herr Goebbels
to film this operation.
He says the film
of these engagements
will outlast us all.
Victory will outlast us all.
This is not victory.
All depends on where
you put the camera.
Did he think he could
waltz his army
into the sector,
like sightseers
on holiday?
All is lost.
The troops have retreated.
Many are dead or wounded.
I know.
I was there.
We must respond
with overwhelming force
immediately.
From the reichsfuhrer.
Reichsfuhrer Himmler
promised Hitler
a Warsaw free of Jews
by his birthday
tomorrow.
You understand this?
If other Jews are
emboldened by this...
Turn of events,
other sectors
initiate their
own uprisings,
it spreads to the poles.
You see
the implications?
See the cause
for concern?
Under orders
of the high command,
you are relieved
of your post forthwith.
Oh.
And to avoid
any unnecessary strain
between
German-Austrian factions
in the SS ranks...
The order
for your execution
has been withdrawn.
You're dismissed.
We're still here.
Who would have bet on it?
We have some real weapons
to fight back with.
Julian, well done.
Look.
Our little nation.
Did you ever think
in your lifetime
you would see this?
What is he doing?
Either he's showing his troops
that he's not afraid,
or he really
likes his table.
Give those out
to the officers.
Good for their nerves.
How can you sleep
at a time like this?
Easily.
Dr. hippler.
Yes, sir.
I don't care
where you put the camera,
just don't film the flags.
But it makes
for a better story.
They show what
our soldiers
had to overcome in order
to achieve victory.
And general Kruger
was quite--
you are not
to shoot the flags.
Unless general Kruger
shows up personally
and instructs you to do so.
Is that clear?
Crystal clear.
I should wake Marek.
Marek, wake up!
Wait.
Now?
Not yet.
Now.
6 more.
Dozens of our men
were killed,
more wounded,
at the brushmaker's.
Pull the tank out!
Further.
No. Further.
Hold! Hold your positions!
Hold your positions!
Stand clear!
It's in the air!
Hold your positions!
Quickly!
Far enough?
Dear Yitzhak,
I don't know
what to write you.
Let's dispense with
the personal details this time.
I've only one expression
to describe my feelings
and the feelings
of my comrades.
Things have surpassed
our boldest dreams."
"The Germans ran away
"from the ghetto twice.
"One of our units
"held out for 14 minutes
"and the other one
for more than 6 hours.
"Know that the pistol
has no value.
Practically
don't use it."
"We need grenades,
rifles, machine guns,
"and explosives.
Your friend in arms,
Mordechai."
Yes, I did say that,
reichsfuhrer Himmler.
They are crafty,
but we will put
an immediate end
to this uprising.
No, not today.
2, 3 days, perhaps.
Excuse me.
Yes, of course.
Yes, reichs--uh...
Feuer!
Aaahhh!
Now it is serious.
Go. Get down
in the basement now!
Come here!
Bring everyone in
from the roof!
Get Calel in!
Mira! Get Calel!
Pull back!
Bring everybody in!
Feuer!
Get out of here!
Go through there!
Hurry! To the right!
To the right!
Zachariah.
Where is Gisl?
The vineyards.
Ohh!
Ohh...
Theo! Mikael!
They're to be sent
to the fighters right away.
Right away.
I have corrected
your mistake.
There were
no casualties today.
There are
no mistakes.
There were--
there are
no mistakes now!
Have you apprehended
the leaders yet?
Not yet, sir. I've--
I'm not looking
for an explanation!
I'm looking for
an acceptable answer.
And that would be,
"yes,
we have captured and
destroyed the leadership."
Heil, Hitler.
I have a message
from Himmler.
I have just begun to get us out
of this disgraceful situation.
Do you wish to hear
what the reichsfuhrer
has to say?
Of course.
As a lover of Wagner,
he said
that you conducted
the overture to this grand
operation magnificently,
particularly compared
to Von Sammern.
He went on to say,
"play on, maestro.
The fuhrer and I
won't forget you."
We in London
now have in our possession
concrete information concerning
the systematic mass murder
of the Jewish population
in Poland
committed by
the German nation.
The Polish courier must
have gotten through.
There is no other way
they could've gotten
those details so right.
If the allies would
bomb the railroads
or the camps
or even Warsaw itself,
we will have a chance.
I don't know.
Do you really think?
Sure.
The scum Calel.
Jewish
police scum!
What is he
doing here?!
Leave him!
No, no, no!
Get off of me!
I'll kill you
with my own hands!
He's one of us!
Get off!
Get him
out of here!
He killed
my father!
They're right...
What they said.
I did.
I know, and
you know I know.
But we don't have--
listen to me.
We don't have time
to dwell on the past.
There's only time to plan
for our immediate future.
Mordechai.
The weapons didn't
make it through.
Yitzhak?
Our shipment of weapons was
intercepted by the Germans
in the cemetery.
And the Germans
discovered the tunnel
at Muranowsky.
It was
no longer safe.
Today is Easter,
right?
Tosia, you're going
out for some fresh air.
You must take
these explosives
and get them to Mordechai
no matter what.
You must get them
to the fighters.
Do you hear?
Get back, everybody!
Get back!
Back.
Out
for a Sunday stroll...
Jew bitch?
We're now going to follow
you around all day.
3,000 zlotys,
or we introduce you
to the gestapo.
Ha ha! Ha! Ok!
Let's go.
No, come. Let's go. I want
to see the little room.
What little room?
The little room
the gestapo reserves
for really, really
pathetic crooks
who waste their time
turning in fellow poles.
Yes, I understand
that those thugs
are given
the full treatment.
So, let's go.
The door!
I will create a diversion!
* Dominus vobiscum *
* et cum spiritu tuum *
Strip the women naked!
This won't happen again.
Get the ladder.
Now, that's
a fine marksman.
They call them
parachutists
or balloonists.
They've devised
a game
whereby the winner
is he who delivers
the most bullets
to the jumper
before he hits
the ground.
Films and photographs
of this kind of operation
will be invaluable
to future historians
of the third Reich.
They'll also be useful
as training materials
for the SS...
And as living document
of the sacrifices
that the Nordic
races made
to rid Europe and
the world of the Jews.
All the exits
are blocked.
Well, we can't stay here.
We have to leave now.
How? If there's
no way out,
we'll be
easy targets.
I'll go out first.
I'll get
their attention.
What are you
talking about?
You once asked me,
"can a moral man
maintain his moral code
in an immoral world?"
Here's my answer.
Aah!
Rot in hell,
you bastards!
Corpus Christi...
Aaahhh!
Paradise lost.
Follow me.
Julian, guard the rear.
All right. All right.
It's kazik.
Quick.
Follow me.
Deworah. Zachariah.
This way.
The relativity Jew,
Albert Einstein,
masked his hatred
of Germans
behind his obscure
pseudo-sciences.
The art of propaganda
is not well understood,
is it?
Keep it simple,
repeat it over and over
until it takes on
a life of its own.
Becomes the truth,
in effect.
We are not
the only one, sir,
fighting the war
on the film front.
The allies have hired
frank Capra
to direct their efforts.
Should I know
that name?
He's a very successful
Hollywood filmmaker.
A little sappy
for my taste, but...
At the top of his game.
Seems the Americans
weren't all that
interested
in going to war,
so he was
brought in to...
Popularize
the notion.
Worse still,
he stole footage
that I commissioned
and used it for ridicule.
As I say...
It all depends on
where you put the camera
and who is telling
the story.
These are not
the Aryan women
from my hometown
Detmold.
They are acrobatic
sharpshooters,
fighting demons.
Amazons.
I don't believe this business
about Jewish women
bewitching Aryans.
She is expressive,
though.
Careful with the basket.
Up, up. Are you sure
you're all right?
Have you hurt
yourself?
What have you
brought us?
Ahh. Dynamite.
Ahh. Excellent.
Commander Zuckerman,
you understand
that the considerations
we face today
are extremely complex.
Of course.
There are those
in the home army,
those here
and in London
that feel the transfer
of weapons to...
Untrained Jewish
street fighters
is a futile
and wasteful use
of our limited resources.
And what if this Jewish
uprising were to spread?
The Polish underground
is hardly equipped
to take on German forces.
Thousands of poles
would be slaughtered,
and we cannot
allow that to happen.
May I remind you,
colonel,
that we, too,
are Polish citizens.
Perhaps these influences
in the home army
are secretly grateful
to the Nazis
for ridding
their country of Jews.
I pray to god
you can rise above
those influences.
The considerations
we face are complex.
That may be.
But you see, colonel,
the considerations
my people face
are simple.
In fact,
I would have to say
that the considerations
my people face
are positively
elemental.
We must have arms.
We must have
explosives.
We must have something
other than our fists
and--and bricks
and our unbreakable
will.
Immediately!
You take no risk!
And if you fail to act,
our blood
will be on your hands.
Mommy!
Shh, shh, shh!
No!
Mommy!
Hands up!
Check the holes!
Take your clothes
off!
Right now! Hands up!
Your plan sounds
reasonable...
And your reports
to Himmler
make it seem as if
things were going well.
But they aren't,
now, are they?
General Kruger...
In a very short while,
the Jewish sector of Warsaw
will be no more.
Every building will be
razed to the ground.
Then we will
bring these vermin
to the surface
or bury them.
In a short while?
This little group
of bandits
have held off
the German military
for longer than
the entire country of Poland.
Is that a short while?
It would make
your job and mine easier
if your reports
weren't so...Optimistic...
And our casualties
were...
Grab the guns
and the ammo!
Shall we say, less,
to be perfectly blunt.
Jan.
No luck.
The poles won't give
us any more weapons.
And you?
None.
Any word from tosia?
The others are secure.
Follow me.
Where?
There's a bunker
at Mila 18.
These are your
fighters, kazik?
Yes.
Ok, go.
Schmuel Asher,
Mordechai Anielewicz.
Hello.
Hi.
I've heard about you
and your group.
Now...
Let me show you around
my basement empire.
Auschwitz,
Treblinka,
Sobibor.
And there is Mauthausen.
We have running water.
We have electricity.
But it's too hot...
And the dust is horrible
for my allergies.
Come on. I'll show you
something, guys.
There are 5 entrances
and 5 exits.
They come in handy
in my line of work.
This way.
Who's winning?
Whatever is ours
is yours.
Well, um...
Not really everything.
Ha ha ha.
Sorry, I can't.
It's all right.
Tuvia was unable to make it
to the inside via the sewers.
I'll go.
No, you won't.
Not until your ankle heals.
Kazik, I want you to go,
and, uh...
Bring zygmunt with you.
Ha. Oh, that's perfect.
Tuvia couldn't
make the cross,
so we send kazik.
What makes you think
we can succeed?
Because you're going
to go through the tunnel.
What tunnel?
The tunnel
at Muranowska.
There's a tunnel there
for special occasions.
The question is...
How safe is it?
Yes. Yes, that is
a good question.
Yeah. It's risky,
but it's worth it.
If Yitzhak has found
guns and supplies,
we can hold off
for a while longer.
Even if he hasn't,
it's critical that we find
a way in and out of the ghetto.
We're playing cat and mouse
with stroop and his men.
We can't hold out forever.
Yesterday we were seeking
safe passage to Palestine.
Today we seek safe passage
across the street.
Our world has gotten
pretty small, eh?
Luck.
Go. Make me proud.
Make yourself proud.
Let's go, Romeo.
I'm instructing
zivia and Marek
to assemble a small squad.
Their mission will be
to find an exit
out of the ghetto
through the sewer canals.
This is going to be
very difficult,
if not impossible,
as we know.
The maze of canals
is vast and confusing.
Those who...
Wish to leave
will be given
the opportunity.
Those who wish to stay
will do so.
Perhaps it will be
possible to...
Connect with the partisans
in the forest
and to continue our fight.
Perhaps not.
But throughout
our difficult struggle,
we have been determined
to preserve one choice.
How we die.
Whether it be here,
in an airless bunker,
or elsewhere,
I don't know.
But I can assure you
of one thing.
The spirit of our deaths...
Ahem.
The spirit of our deaths
will shape the soul
of a new generation.
A new nation of Jews.
All right.
Let's wish zivia
and Marek luck.
Luck!
And we continue.
You're a sight
for sore eyes.
So are you.
And...
Julian?
He's our best
marksman.
Oh...
No, no, kazik,
it's all right!
It's all right!
Tell me.
Something is not right.
What?
The level of fighting
has decreased.
They only attack us
at night.
They're
playing possum.
The gestapo's informer
has told us
where their
command bunker is,
and this time, they
think it's accurate.
Well, that is good news,
isn't it?
Too good.
Too easy.
Is your ankle better?
Yes.
If you want to go, you can.
It's up to you.
I'd rather stay here
and fight
with you and arie,
if that's all right.
It's all right.
Where are
the sewer workers?
I don't know
what happened.
They were paid
to guide us.
But they haven't
shown up.
We need to go now.
This is far
too dangerous for you.
No. We are going into
the ghetto tonight,
if not through the sewers,
over the wall.
Are you
out of your mind?
We have no chance
without a plan.
Nor do the fighters
if we don't
get them out.
How will we do that
if we are shot?
I am going.
How do you intend
to get them out?
Are you with me
or not?
We have no chance to succeed
without a Polish guide
to take us into the sewers
and out again.
Do you see a guide?!
Do you?
There is no sewer worker!
Are you with me on that?
I will go with you,
Yitzhak.
Well, you can make
your own funeral
arrangements.
I will not carry
your coffin!
I will accompany you.
But he makes sense.
Maybe we should try again
tomorrow with the poles.
We can't rely
on the poles, frania.
We can't rely on anyone else
to get us in!
Zivia, when you get
down to the sewer, go left.
And let's hope
for the best.
I will cover your escape.
Go. Before you forget
why you're leaving.
We'll be back.
Goodbye, Zachariah.
Be good, Zach.
Oh, come on.
You're already a day late!
Let's go!
Follow me.
Tell our friends to keep
their spirits up.
Ugh.
Oh!
Show me.
This way.
I just wish we had
more weapons and ammunition.
That would be really
something, huh?
What is it?
I just had
the most, uh...
Ridiculous dream.
It was so...Vivid.
I was sleeping,
and your sister
Gina came
and woke me up,
and she took me
outside to this...
Beautiful garden.
And there were grapes
and nuts and figs.
That's very biblical,
huh?
And then
she took me to a...
Basket.
And there was a...
A baby inside it.
And...
She said that he was
my...
My child.
And I took him,
and I held him
in my arms.
Tell me the history
of the eternal Jew.
How did this film of yours
come to be?
Goebbels
commissioned it.
It was, uh...His idea.
His pet project.
He felt that Germans
were not antisemitic enough.
It didn't come as easy
to them as, say,
the poles or the French
or even the English.
The film was the...
Psychological underpinning
of the fuhrer's plan
for racial purity.
Why do you think
these Jewish women
are such ferocious
fighters?
Desperation?
I've never witnessed this
before.
I saw one woman...
Shot several times.
As she was dying,
she cursed me
in a language
that was beyond vile.
I can't get the image
out of my mind.
Maybe you're
bewitched.
Here's to good bewitching.
Out!
Shh!
Quiet!
Check that tunnel.
See if it's passable,
Mira.
Tosia, down there.
Deworah.
Down there, Julian.
They can't have found
all 5 exits.
Hurry!
Blocked.
Completely blocked.
Mira!
No, it's not safe.
Julian!
It's clear.
Yes?
We can make it out
through the sewer.
Maybe there is
a way to the sewers
through the cellar wall.
That way?
Yeah.
All right. Tosia,
go with Byah.
See if it's possible,
all right?
Mira! Mira! Hurry!
Go! Hurry!
We need reinforcements.
Spread out and try
to outflank them.
Find Zachariah.
Spread out
and create a diversion.
Hurry up, Gina.
Die!
The ghetto's
through this.
Good. Lead me.
No. I go no further.
You have been paid
to lead me.
I show you.
That's all.
As a member
of the home army,
it is
my assigned mission
to rescue
Christian poles
trapped in the ghetto.
If you do not wish
to cooperate,
then I will give you
a simple choice.
Lead me or die.
That is your choice.
Follow me.
Good decision.
The exits are sealed.
The fighters are all dead.
Ok, we stay.
We fight here.
Yeah. Let's go.
Let's go.
This way.
Quickly. Come on.
How much further
till we get to the ghetto?
Everything is sealed.
Is everybody in position?
If you don't
have a gun...
One person,
right through here.
Come on, move!
Every exit.
Julian, go see if tosia
has made any progress.
Right.
Move it! Move!
There's another wall.
Tosia. Tosia.
Have you found an entrance
to the sewer canals?
Not yet.
Hurry.
We are.
Mordechai,
I don't think
they'll make it
through soon enough.
I'm sorry.
All right, Julian.
Take your position.
You've done well.
I wonder if zivia
and the group
made it through.
Zivia will find
a way out.
I would have bet that
kazik found a way back.
I would have bet
on him.
He won't
disappoint you.
Mira, let me
ask you a question.
How is it you
always be
so positive,
so optimistic,
so, uh...
So supportive?
I'm lucky.
To luck, huh?
To luck.
Isaac, Sarah,
go through right now.
I'll go get Mordechai.
This way.
If you sense gas,
cover your faces
with a wet cloth
and stay low.
Cover your face and stay
low to the ground.
I found a way out!
Mordechai!
I found a way out
through the sewer!
Stay low!
Low to the ground!
Keep low.
Mordechai!
Save the last bullet
for yourself.
Help me, Mordechai!
Everyone follow me this way!
Now! I found the way out!
Let's give them a greeting
they'll remember.
Mordechai!
Zivia!
Deworah!
Tosia!
Kazik?
Kazik?!
Tosia.
Kazik.
Tosia?
Where are the others?
A few of us made it out
to the sewers, but...
Mordechai and Mira...
And almost all the rest
died here in the bunker.
How did you get in?
I thought...
I was the last Jew
in the ghetto.
The last one.
Kazik.
Kazik!
How did you get in?
Through the sewer canals.
Then you will take us out.
No...
Yes.
Come.
No.
Kazik, come!
I want to stay here.
There are others
who need our help.
No...
Paradise.
This way.
In the tunnel.
All right.
Wait.
Shh. Shh.
Get back.
Paradise.
Paradise?
Yes.
Kazik?!
Tosia!
It's a miracle!
We were lost.
We've been walking
in circles.
It's like a miracle!
Kazik, tell me,
have you been
to the other side?
Yes, he has.
Then he is
our leader.
All right.
Ok.
Good luck, everyone.
Quickly and quietly.
Follow me.
Come on. Come, Sarah.
Heil Hitler.
One of major Hoffer's
SS informants
says some of the leaders
are still alive.
He's heard that
they've taken the sewers
to the Aryan side to join up
with the partisans
and continue to fight.
The major wanted me
to inform you of this
as soon as possible.
Yitzhak,
we need a truck.
We need it
for 2 nights.
Trucks are expensive.
I wish I could.
I thought you might
say this.
Turn back.
No.
Wait. Wait.
All right.
Under here.
It's all right.
Watch your head.
Come under here.
Under here.
All right. Zivia.
Ok.
Come through.
Ah!
Now...tosia.
She must be quick.
The water's rising.
Come through.
Where's the boy
and the girl?
Sarah.
He's coming through.
Isaac, come here.
I'll go up here.
Right here, Isaac.
Go slowly ahead!
All right,
is everybody through?
We've got to get
through quickly.
Coming through!
The baby's gone!
My baby!
Come on.
It's shut.
It's welded shut.
It's welded shut!
Please don't panic.
Don't push. Be calm.
A little bit further on,
it opens out
to a canal.
That's the beginning
of the Aryan side.
Well, we are
across the street
from the Aryan side,
but there is no one
waiting for us up above.
We cannot hold on
any longer.
There is nowhere to take
all these people
out on the street
without a truck
to get us out of the city.
Kazik...
You go by yourself.
We'll go back,
find an exit.
Yes, tonight.
Jan.
Where is it?
I don't know.
They're late.
We can't afford late.
There's been a delay.
They will try again later.
We must keep everyone calm.
I'll let them know.
Yes. An office.
54 Proster street.
Office furniture.
Cabinets.
No, just the driver.
We have our own laborers.
You can?
We must have water.
We must have food.
Please, stay calm.
We're doing all we can.
It's not enough.
I would rather
die on the street
with a German bullet.
You will do exactly
as you are instructed.
Now be quiet.
There is another
landing down there.
Go! Get out
of the water.
The people
cannot take any more!
Silence yourself.
Do you think I will
let your weakness
jeopardize the lives
of these people?
Have any notion
the sacrifices
these fighters have made
so that you can be
here alive?
I know--
alive on the verge
of freedom!
I want to get out!
Don't think for a moment
that I will hesitate
to put a bullet
through your skull,
fulfill your wish,
if you keep
this foolishness up.
Shut up!
Where is your office?
I don't see it.
In the basement.
Oh! What is this?
This is your chance
to be a hero before god.
Drive.
Pull over there.
Please,
quickly and quietly,
and do exactly
as kazik instructs.
Marek, why are we doing
this in broad daylight?
Because we are.
You're mad.
You were right.
Are there many more?
Yes, there are more.
How many?
40 on this landing
and a dozen
on another landing.
We can't wait.
They will come.
I promised them.
One more minute.
One minute,
and then we leave.
I'll get them.
We don't have
enough time.
I'll get them.
Quickly, quickly.
20 more.
Come, come, come,
come, come, come.
This is an operation
of the Polish underground.
And I believe in
Santa Claus.
Well, Santa...
This is a pistol
I'm pointing in your ribs.
Do you believe that?
Yes.
Then you will also believe
that I won't hesitate
to splatter your guts
all over the cobblestones
unless you do
exactly as I say.
You stay there.
Into the truck.
10 more.
Hurry up! Hurry! Now!
They're Jews.
That's everyone
on this landing.
14 total. Come, kazik.
That's it.
I am not leaving
without them.
You are putting us all
at risk.
I am not asking you,
I am telling you.
Zivia.
Get on the truck.
Zivia...
We will come back
for them.
Go.
Go! Go! Go!
Go, go, go, go!
Go! Go!
They've escaped.
It seems to be so.
I'm going to have you
communicate
to reichsfuhrer Himmler
that Warsaw
will be free of Jews
tomorrow.
My engineers
have prepared dynamite
in the Jews' synagogue.
Further,
I've informed Himmler
that the remainder
of our work here
will be carried out
by the local police
under my control.
Now, you may
even receive
a commendation
for your efforts.
But between you and me,
you let the bandits
get away.
I want everything
brought up!
Every body, every corpse,
every piece of evidence!
And then seal it shut.
Tighter than
the pharaoh's tomb,
and every manhole cover
in Warsaw
I want welded shut!
Every single one!
Enough!
Mordechai Anielewicz
sent me this letter
shortly before
his last battle.
I want to read
a part of it to you.
"Our fighters
have endured conditions
"beyond description.
"Yet they have persevered--
"no, more than persevered.
"They have conquered
these conditions
"and fought on bravely
"over and over
"and over again.
"Perhaps we shall
meet again.
Perhaps."
"But the main thing is,
"the dream of my life
has come true.
"I have lived to see
a Jewish defense
"in the ghetto
"in all its greatness
and glory."
Let us remember Mordechai
and all the others,
and let us continue.
Let us continue to fight on.
Look, kazik.
Look how deeply
they breathe.
Each breath...
So peaceful, so rhythmic.
Yes.
One after another
after another...
After another.