wanna speak real English from your first
lesson sign up for your free lifetime
account at English class 101.com
hi everybody my name is Alisha and I am
joined again in the studio by Michael
hello and today we're going to be
talking about English conversation
strategies so let's get right into it
let's start with Michael what is your
first strategy for keeping an english
conversation going this is very
important don't say I'm fine thank you
and you you hear this all the time from
second language English learners or
non-native speakers you learn this it's
one of the first things you learn in an
English class it's easy it's good its
basic its foundation okay that's fine
but as soon as you can switch it up
because to me when I meet a foreigner
and they come up and if they say hey how
are you say oh I'm fine you know I'm
good whatever how about you and they say
I'm fine thank you and you and it's just
it's almost robotic because I've said it
so many times and when I hear that I
think their English isn't that good and
inside I'm just gonna be really polite
and say hello and talk slowly and try to
get out of there as quick as I can
so really impress the foreigner in my
opinion I think the best way to do it is
say something you know you use a big
word or just like a slang word something
like that when I hear that I go wow man
I want to know what this person thinks I
want to get their point of view and I'm
really excited and then I've had great
conversations because of that um yeah
that's a really really good one and
actually I think on this YouTube channel
actually from a couple years ago there's
a video all about better answers to the
question how are you then I'm fine thank
you and you or if someone says hey how
are you I'm good
you are fine you never I'm fine thank
you and you never but try to actually
use you know afraid that a native
speaker would use and then that's a clue
to the native speaker that oh maybe this
person is ready for a conversation
beyond you know basic English so that's
a really good point I like that I didn't
think of things not to do I only thought
of things to do oh okay
cool um let's see let's go to my first
one oh so this strategy in general is
just ask the other person a question I
think and I'm guilty of this too when
I'm learning another language I tend to
only get input like somebody else is
always asking me the questions and then
I forget myself to ask the other person
a question so one question that I like
to ask or you know a variation any kind
of WH question is good like a food
question what where something like this
if you've been paying attention you can
use any way to transition in your
conversation this was in a previous
video you can ask something like anyway
up to anything fun this weekend
this is a pretty casual conversational
question than she can ask just about
anybody whether you've just met them or
whether you've known them for a while
but just just get in the habit of asking
other people the question don't wait for
someone else to ask you the question so
that that's one strategy that I try to
use to keep things going
yeah me too I agree and I'm gonna say
samesies because actually two of my
questions were exactly what you said
agree 100% this is kind of cheating
these should be one but so always ask
questions so you know again you forget
it's really easy I'm really guilty of
this English non English whatever I'm
guilty of this and the other thing is
ask deep open-ended questions so if you
ask a yes-or-no question so again like
Alicia was saying it just dead ends you
can't just say you know do you like
cheese yes or no right so you want to
say what do you think about cheese what
is your favorite kind and kind of open
it up to something else and let it let
it just kind of snowball yeah I think I
think that's that's really a key like I
have another variation I wish I guess
I'll just continue on because it kind of
relates to what you're talking about
like he's saying always ask questions
always ask deep open-ended questions so
like you meant you just said don't ask a
yes-or-no question because yes or no
ends with the yes or the no so one of
the things that I'll do is use a pattern
similar to this like hey did you see or
hey did you hear about blah blah blah so
you can use this little blah blah blah
as your you can ask about the news you
can ask about something funny you saw on
the internet you can ask about you know
some something that you heard from
another friend of yours whatever it's
just a way to check in with the other
person and say oh did you also
experience this thing that I experienced
let's talk about that so that might be
another question that you can use with
people I like that one I really like
that one because you got to stay within
people's comfort zone so maybe you asked
and maybe they don't want to write so a
good thing is did you hear about it
that's up to them maybe they don't want
to talk about it they can say oh yeah I
heard about that and you can kind of
feel the the atmosphere and and realize
maybe I shouldn't talk about this change
the subject or they get passionate and
they start talking about it and there
you go and just let it go
yeah absolutely one thing again I'm
guilty of is is you do got to keep keep
returning it right
don't just say oh yeah and what I think
about that uh bring you back ask them
what about you that's a common thing I
forget about yeah yeah yeah okay um good
I have one more this one um use when you
see Fitz don't I guess just okay I'll
just introduce it compliment the other
person or compliment the other person's
this can be a nice strategy just to show
that you're enjoying the other person's
company it can be as simple as oh I like
your shirt today or oh that's a nice
dress you're wearing today or oh did you
get a new haircut that looks good on you
something like that so this is a nice a
nice way to make the other person maybe
you want to spend more time with you
I think yeah I agree 100% two things one
I think it's a good conversation starter
sometimes if you've got to be careful
with the stranger it can be creepy it
can be a little uncomfortable what
you're complimenting right but if it's
something like if they have a t-shirt
and it's a band that you both like
that's a great conversation starter and
you feel wow we're connected you know
number two the second thing I was
thinking about is that keep it honest I
love I love a sincere compliment it
really means a lot more and and it
really does butter them up kind of get
them open to having more conversations
deeper that kind of thing but one of the
things people do which which I don't
like is let's say they say hey nice
shirt and then the person out of habit
will say oh you too I like your shirt
too just my opinion I don't think this
feels really natural doesn't really feel
sincere so I would I would save it make
a mental note and go hmm I need to
return the favor I need to give them a
compliment but wait until you notice
something you really do like and say hey
actually I love blah blah blah yeah I
think that's a great point like when you
you can sense whether someone is being
sincere or not what is your next
strategy for continuing an English
conversation well don't be afraid to
open up I like this one I think this is
good a lot of people will be kind of shy
they won't open up too much again within
within your comfort zone but I like this
one because people will return the favor
because if you're just having small talk
and you say you know the weather is nice
today blah blah blah you can only go so
far so don't be afraid to say something
personal again
trust your judgment there'll be a
creeper don't go we don't want to hear
certain things about your life don't
don't be a creep don't be a creep don't
be weird don't be strange and like what
you're saying about opening up open up
is just a phrase that means to share
something about yourself so it can be as
simple as what you did last weekend or
what you're going to do this weekend or
a project that you have coming up it
doesn't mean that you have to spill all
of your life secrets to the other person
but just showing that you're willing to
share something more personal about
yourself can help ingratiate yourself or
can help you know make the other person
help the other person understand you a
little bit better that's a good tip I
like that tip that's hard to do though
it's hard it's a little bit scary I
think to share parts of yourself but
it's good it's good way to meet people
and make friends all right I think
that's all is that all that you have
yeah that's all I got okay all right
well those are some interesting
strategies to keep an english
conversation going so give them a try if
you're ever at a loss for words and
don't know what to say you can try one
of these strategies and hopefully it
will help you out please let us know if
you have any other strategies or
anything else that you would like to use
or you try to use when you are having
trouble keeping a conversation going
leave us a comment and let us know what
it is top ten language learning
strategies let's begin the friending or
dating someone who speaks English
watching movies or listening to music in
English read English newspapers or
magazines record your voice and compare
your pronunciation with native English
speakers download dialog tracks and
listen to English conversations repeat
the phrases that you hear out loud again
and again review all the lessons on
English class 101.com
to master them completely read lines
slowly at first then reread and increase
your speed set small and measurable
learning goals with your personal
deadlines try harder lessons to
challenge yourself and improve faster
and ways to stop translating in your
head let's get started
identify objects around you in English
the first way to stop translating in
your head is to identify the objects
around you in your target language so if
you're studying English that means you
look at the objects around the room look
at the things in your life don't think
of them in your native language first
think of them in your target language
first so if I look around the room I see
a computer I shouldn't think my native
language word I should think my target
language words so start with the items
and the situations in your everyday life
if I say computer in English maybe I
should say computer in Japanese I should
say not I don't know water in English I
should say Oh Mesa in Japanese so start
associating the words in your target
language with your everyday life now so
if you're studying English that means
start getting familiar with the things
in your everyday life in English repeat
phrases you hear native speakers use tip
number two is to repeat the phrases that
you hear native speakers use so if
you're watching this channel for example
or you're watching a TV show or a movie
listen for the way that native speakers
make those phrases if you hear a phrase
you have never heard before or you hear
an interesting combination of words try
to repeat them yourself don't just
listen try to save them yourself
if you're in a public space and it's
difficult for you to do that fine
practice in a place where you feel more
comfortable maybe if you have some
private space to practice just repeat
them get your mouth used to saying the
words the way that the speakers the
native speakers do so if you never
actually say words if you're only taking
in if you're only listening and you're
not actually producing the language it's
it's kind of hard to to practice and to
to really hone your pronunciation to
improve your pronunciation so when you
listen to native speakers try to repeat
after them so for example if you're
studying English you can try to repeat
after this video you can repeat after
the things I'm saying because maybe I'm
using an expression or I'm using a
certain series of vocabulary words
together the way a native speaker would
and it's maybe a good idea to try to
practice the ways that native speakers
put their words together so try to
repeat after native speakers especially
when you're looking at media and you can
do this when you're reading books too
you can try to read out read out loud
interesting lines of books that you find
or something that maybe is difficult for
you very nice practice to make a
situation where you can't escape into
your native language make a situation
where you can't escape into your native
language essentially means immerse
yourself of course going to that country
are going to a place where you can speak
only that language is very difficult for
some of you totally understand but if in
your life you can create a situation in
your library in your room in your house
somewhere for just an hour or I don't
know maybe a day I don't know what your
schedule is like but if you can create a
situation or create an environment where
you have no choice but to use that
language and you cannot escape meaning
you cannot go back to using your native
language as a crutch you can't use the
native language at all it forces you to
use the language that you're studying so
of course if you are lucky enough to
live in the country or to live in a
place where people speak the language
you're studying great but you have to go
out and interact with people you have to
put yourself in a place where you have
no choice but to speak it's very hard
and it's very scary and it's very
embarrassing at first but if you take
time to find places and to make
environments that are comfortable for
you where you feel comfortable making
mistakes and asking questions it's very
valuable for your learning process this
is actually something that I did totally
I totally did this my Japanese wasn't
very good for a long time but then I
started making friends who could not
speak English actually I just did this
through finding high
these there was a hobby that I had I
joined a group I joined actually a
school to where I could learn how to do
that hobby and everything was taught
only in Japanese and the people in my
class only spoke Japanese mostly and
then maybe we would go out for drinks
and food late at night or on the
weekends and everybody spoke only
Japanese and if I couldn't communicate
even simply in Japanese I had no hope of
keeping that friendship together so it
forced me to study it forced me to think
about the words they were using and to
try to learn those words those patterns
as well as how to produce them naturally
myself so I was learning the vocabulary
words the people around me were using
and learning how to apply them on my own
that was only possible because I had no
escape in those situations so try to do
that even if you can do it yourself in
your house it's super helpful I think
watch TV and movies in your target
language without subtitles tip number
four is to watch TV and movies in your
target language without subtitles
without subtitles so I think that
watching with subtitles can be very
beneficial so if I'm watching something
or if you want to watch something with
subtitles on great but I sometimes find
that I can in my case I think too much
about reading the subtitles and I forget
to listen so maybe if you've seen a
movie in your target language a few
times with the subtitles on try turning
the subtitles off and think about the
like character's body language the words
they're using you can always look that
up later look up the you know the words
you don't know in a dictionary but try
to do it where you're focusing
completely on the way that people are
using their words try not to use the
subtitles so kind of play around with it
a little bit if there's a word that's
difficult for you to hear you can
actually turn on the subtitles in like
the in the native language of the movie
as well that's something that I've done
like if like if I wanted to study
Japanese it's very useful when the
actual words
Okin in Japanese appear on the screen
sometimes it's easier for me to catch a
word if I see it visually and I hear it
at the same time so another way to kind
of explore how you can use TV and movies
is to actually turn on the closed
captions like the the words on the
screen in the native language of the
movie so so this is sort of two points
in one so one watch movies without
subtitles
meaning subtitles in your native
language and hint to is to watch movies
with closed captioning on but the closed
captioning is in your target language
not in your native language so you can
try those two things with TV and with
movies don't bring a dictionary to your
lesson tip number five is don't bring a
dictionary to your lesson okay so it
gives me a second here so I understand
the dictionaries it was especially
electronic dictionaries we have them on
our phones now are very very convenient
of course it's important to use them and
it's a they're a great resource to have
however one thing that really bothers me
and that I think is detrimental it's not
helpful for students is when students
are in a lesson and they're practicing
conversation and they reach a point in
the conversation where they don't know
the word they want to use they know it
in their native language and they don't
know how to say it in their target
language they pull out their dictionary
they say to this the person listening to
them their practice partner in their
lesson where they have a limited period
of time just a moment and then they look
it up on the phone it takes a few
seconds the flow of the conversation
stops and then they say a word it's like
whoa no that's not you don't have that
ability you don't have the ability to do
that in a conversation with a native
speaker most people like if you go to a
bank and try to open a bank account are
you really going to pull out your
dictionary and sit there and try to
communicate you know just a moment just
a moment as you look up each word you
don't know no or if you do that's not
a real conversation so instead try using
a different strategy by that I mean if
you find a word you don't know in
conversation explain the word to your
conversation partner maybe they know the
word if you're speaking with a native
speaker this is a chance for them to
teach you a word I find that when people
take the time to teach me a word
I remember the word much better than
just looking it up on my dictionary so
try to resist maybe you can bring a
dictionary to your lesson but don't use
it or try not to use it in your
conversation practice it's just it
destroys the flow of a conversation
so instead practice the skill of
describing the vocabulary word you want
to use and learn how to ask the meaning
of a word or learn how to ask for a
vocabulary word from your partner so you
can use an expression like ah what's the
word that means pop habla or you know
it's this thing that does this and this
and this so this is an opportunity for
you to describe characteristics of
something or find a different way you
can use your body language you can use
whatever you have a lot of tools but try
not to use a dictionary in a
conversation because it's not realistic
train responses to common questions
number six is a quick one I think number
six hint number six I have is just to
Train responses to common questions
train responses to common questions so
for example a very common question in
English is hey how are you you should
know how to answer this question just
have a default response hey how are you
I'm good if it takes you a long time to
answer the question hey how are you you
need to practice I think that's a pretty
good a pretty good indicator so for
example sometimes I ask students a
question like that they haven't quite
gotten the idea of how to respond just
yet they're not so quick at responding I
say hey how are you and they say yes and
then they think and they go I am I'm a
good and it's like that's a very common
question so think about
the default response that you can spit
out that you can quickly say if it's how
was your weekend or hey what's up or
what do you want to do for dinner
tonight think about like just a handful
meaning just a few responses to those
questions and train them quickly just
how are you I'm good how are you I'm
okay how are you not bad there's three
so it's just training responses to those
questions there's no reason to be
surprised by a question like how are you
like that's a very common question so
for those common questions trained
responses to that we've got a bunch of
videos especially beginner level videos
for some example responses you can do so
don't get stuck with these little
questions just train a few responses
practice a few responses till they feel
natural to you it'll save you time and
it'll help the person asking the
question to to move forward in the
conversation okay
study with materials that don't provide
a translation the next tip is to study
with materials that don't provide a
translation so by this I mean if you're
using worksheets or some kind of
textbook
or whatever and it has your target
language the language you're studying
and it has your native language next to
it while this can be useful I feel that
if you can studying your materials only
in your target language and then
simplified explanations for more
detailed points also in your target
language can be a little bit better so I
don't want to say like you should only
study things in your target language and
nothing from your native language
because of course like it can be helpful
sometimes to look up a word or to
understand a grammar point in your
native language but where possible if
you can find something that provides
simplified explanations in your target
language it can be really really helpful
because again you're thinking you're
learning to think on like a simpler on a
more basic level about the language
you're studying in the language that
you're studying so this can be really
really good
so finding some materials to use where
there's no
translation maybe you can practice of
course with with books and with written
materials but also with like video
materials as well so there are a variety
of different ways that you can find
materials in your target language like
in video and TV so some things to think
about there are the level of vocabulary
words people are using in the media
content you're watching who the media
content is intended for children young
adults adults the speed at which the
speaker is talking so like I have the
ability to change the level of
difficulty of videos based on the rate
of speech the vocabulary words that I
use and how many like idioms and things
I use so I could make a video very
difficult we could make a very like a
very difficult video series by levelling
up our vocabulary use or by speaking
very quickly or as you might see in like
our English in three minutes series we
can also use very simple vocabulary and
speak at a low rate of speech so maybe
right now this is a very intermediate
level video so please think about that
so not just for written materials but
also for your audio and visual materials
think about who your audience is the
level of the material and so on it can
be really fun and it can be helpful to
think about your your target language in
your target language all right we're all
Muslim study phrases in addition to
single vocabulary the next tip is study
phrases in addition to single vocabulary
words so yes of course vocabulary is
important but I find it personally very
very useful to look at how a vocabulary
word is used in a phrase because
sometimes using it in a phrase helps you
understand the nuance of that vocabulary
word really really well so if I like a
word like crazy for example in English
depending on the situation where the
word crazy is used it could mean
something different it could mean like a
person who is mentally confused or mixed
up it could also mean something really
good it could mean
something really bad so if we look only
at the word crazy it's quite difficult
to understand really the meaning of the
word but if you look at the way the word
is used in a phrase you can get a lot
more information so take a look at the
way people use words in phrases not just
a single vocabulary words you can learn
a lot more that way I think do your
daily activities in English where
possible the next step is to do your
daily activities in your target language
so if you're studying English that means
try to do some daily activities in
English if possible so this can be very
very boring stuff but just think about
it when you're doing the activity so
like right now I'm filming a video for
English class 101.com or I'm going to
work I'm cooking breakfast I'm doing the
laundry what do I have to do tomorrow so
try thinking about your everyday life in
English if you're studying English try
thinking about your everyday activities
the people that you meet what are you
doing so this is a way to help you
practice your verbs so if you don't know
if you're I don't know you're doing
something at work and you're like oh my
gosh how do I explain the what's the
verb for you know a picture like I want
to blah blah blah a picture what's the
word you can check a dictionary at that
point it's draw like I need to use the
verb draw or draw a picture so you can
find these little gaps in your everyday
life these little gaps in your knowledge
if you think about your everyday
activities in your target language if
you don't think about it in your target
language you might not realize you have
vocabulary gaps or phrase gaps here and
there so this is a really good and kind
of funny actually way to study use a
learner's dictionary for new words the
last tip is to use a learner's
dictionary for new words so in English
there are learners dictionaries
available in English so my favorite my
personal favorite is merriam-webster
merriam-webster is a fantastic
dictionary resource they're so
interesting and they have tons of like
historical information I really do just
sit and like readings on the dictionary
page lately it's true
but of course there's a definition
there's a meaning for words there are
example sentences for words but
merriam-webster also has what's called a
learner's dictionary if you find a word
that you don't recognize you can check
it in a dictionary in a learner's
dictionary and it gives you a simplified
a simple explanation in simple English
of that word so instead of checking it
in your native language you can check it
in your target language so again this
helps you to understand the word that
you are that you're focused on but you
understand it from the language you're
studying not from your native language
so using a learner's dictionary can be
really really useful as well yeah all
right
want to get cheat sheets audio books
lessons apps and much more every month
for free just click the link in the
description to get your free language
gifts of the month 10 ways to report
speech let's go say the first word is
say say as a verb say is a very neutral
word you can use to report someone's
speech to explain something someone said
in the past so for example he said the
barbecue was canceled
just a simple neutral report tell the
next verb is tell tell is used when one
person is giving information to another
to tell someone something they did not
know before don't say tell me your phone
number that's weird but like can you
tell me where the station is can you
tell me where to buy a hamburger can you
tell me where to pick up my new car like
so giving someone information they don't
know or or on the other hand explaining
something one way to another person so
don't tell me what I can't do is a very
good lost reference if you've ever
watched lost so tell another example
sentence my boss told me I was doing a
good job
speak the next one is speak speak so we
use speak when we're talking about
language ability like I speak English I
speak Japanese we can use speak in the
past tense
to report something but it usually
sounds a little more formal so like I
spoke to my boss about or I spoke to my
parents about or I spoke to my boyfriend
or girlfriend about bla bla bla that
using speak instead of talked makes it
sound a little bit more formal so you
can use speak but it's going to sound
polite in a sentence my colleagues spoke
with me about an upcoming project was
like ok the next one the next two
actually are very very casual
expressions so when you're speaking with
friends and you're kind of talking about
a quick maybe somewhat emotional
conversation you will hear native
speakers especially Americans perhaps
this is unique somewhat to Americans use
the phrase was like I was like he was
like she was like this is a very casual
way to report speech and you'll hear an
often very very quickly together so
someone will say I was like what and
then she was like no and then I was like
yeah that's the kind of pattern you'll
hear it in very very quick ways to
report speech but the subject changes I
was like he was like she was like we
were like this is a way to share what
happens quickly instead of I said he
said she said which might sound a little
too formal we can use I was like he was
like to do that instead so this is a
really fun one and if you can use this
naturally I think that it'll really help
you sound more natural too so in a
sentence and then he was like I love
that movie was all the next one is also
a similar to was like we have the
expression was all so it was all don't
worry about all all does not have the
meaning of the whole of something or a
complete something instead was all this
set phrase is used to report speech
usually this one is used when there's
some kind of emotional emotional aspect
to your conversation or it's a little
dramatic or maybe a little exciting we
use it the same way as was like in that
very very quick style of speaking and
then he was like and I was all and then
she was like and I was all we used those
together but I was all has a little more
emphasis I feel I tend to use it when my
when I want to express a stronger
emotion and I was all no way or and I
was all what so you can use it for those
very like surprised emotions or maybe
angry emotions was like and was all are
both used in very casual situations so
in a sentence and I was all oh my god me
to talk the next word is talk so talk
similar to say is a fairly neutral verb
when reporting speech you'll use it in a
situation where someone is giving new
information to you but maybe it's a
two-way conversation so for example we
talked about blah blah blah for a topic
or my boss talked to me about blah blah
blah so maybe new information is being
exchanged but the conversation is
two-way there are multiple participants
with tell it's like the nuances sort of
one person is reporting information
giving information with talked it's
there's an exchange happening there so
keep in mind when you use the word talk
you will say either I talked to or I
talked with someone and then you'll
usually have a topic so I talked to my
friend about blah blah blah I talked to
my friend about my new apartment I
talked to my boss about a raise I talked
to my boss know I talked to my dog about
what dogs knew so there's some kind of
there's some kind of exchange happening
there you'll need to use to or with when
you're referring to the person or entity
you're talking to
and you'll use about to refer to the
subject so you can use this one yeah
when you're when you want to discuss
exchanges of information so in a
sentence she talked to me about my
family mention let's go to the next one
the next one is mention mention is used
when like something is just there's just
one small point in a conversation like
just a little side note or maybe it's
not the focus of a conversation but just
something someone says quickly or
there's just a little thing that you
hear oh you mentioned something about
blah blah blah or you mentioned that a
new project like it's it's maybe not the
focus of the conversation but something
that you heard a little bit about that's
that's when we use the verb mention we
can also use it in a statement like
please mention any skills you have on a
resume so it's the nuance is sort of
like a like just a little bit of
information is when we use mention so in
a sentence our manager mentioned
upcoming changes at the company to go on
and on okay the next expression is to go
on and on so to go on and on means just
to talk for a very long time so maybe
you have a co-worker or a friend or
family member that just talks and does
not stop talking we say to go on and on
that's the expression we use so in a
sentence the speaker at the seminar was
going on and on about the topic if you
really want to emphasize it you can say
what's going on and on and on and on and
on that really emphasizes that the
person continues to speak so if you know
somebody who does that a lot you can use
this expression to talk about them
according to the next expression here is
according to according to is used
actually in the news or like to
officially report something so according
to sources or according to the police
according to the government official
according to my teacher according to my
mother these are like direct reports of
information and their direct reports of
in
Meishan from a specific source so
according to the newspaper my
neighborhood has 50,000 amazing ramen
shops that's not true but if I want to
instead of just saying my neighborhood
has 50,000 amazing ramen shops I'm
giving a source for that so according to
my newspaper this is this is where I got
the information so this is important to
use in news and newspapers and any kind
of official documentation you will see
and here
according to in these cases in a
sentence according to a witness at the
scene the suspect escaped report great
so the next one is report so reports
similar to according to we use report in
more official situations so to
officially share information like to
report to the police to report to your
teacher to report to your boss sometimes
it means to submit documentation like to
give someone a written report sometimes
it's to share information officially
just just with your voice to report news
or to report an update so when you want
to give and give official information
we'll use the verb report so in a
sentence sources in the area report that
the accident was not serious thank
goodness all right the top 10 must know
phrases for the restaurant let's get
started a table for three please a table
for three please you tell them the
number of people that you are total so
that the host can bring you to an
appropriate table a table for two please
a table for five please could I please
see a menu could I please see a menu
usually menus are given to you as soon
as you sit down at your table but if
that's not the case and you need to ask
this is a polite way to do it
did I please see a menu I'd like to try
this dish I'd like to try this dish when
looking at a menu hopefully you'll find
something you want to eat I'd like to
try this dish
could you leave out the onions could you
leave out the onions if there's an
ingredient in the dish that you're
ordering that you don't want you can
always ask the waiter if it could be
prepared without that ingredient so for
example I might say can I get the burger
but with no cheese could you pass the
salt could you pass the salt when you're
at a restaurant especially if you're at
a big table with a lot of people you
might not always be able to reach things
so you would ask could you pass me the
salt could you pass me the ketchup could
you pass me another napkin waiter waiter
a waiter is someone who takes your order
and brings you food in America and in
many other Western countries it's more
polite to call a waiter to your table by
simply saying excuse me or if you see
another waiter walking by but it's not
your waiter
you can always say excuse me if you see
our waiter could you please let them
know to come to our table is there any
dairy in this dish is there any dairy in
this dish this is something you would
say if you have a dairy allergy a dairy
intolerance or you just don't like dairy
you're asking the waiter about the
ingredients in a particular dish I do
this all the time is there any cheese in
this No okay and if there is an
ingredient that you don't want for
example onions you could say are there
any onions in this and the waiter might
say yes and if you don't want it you
could always request could you leave out
the onions could you prepare it without
the onions please can we get separate
checks
can we get separate checks this is
actually something that's very common
especially in America if you might go
out with a group of friends or even if
you're on a date sometimes you might
want to get separate checks pay for your
own things that way you can all pay
separately just for what you yourself
ordered and you won't have to worry
about owing each other money or
calculating off a big huge bill are
there any specials today are there any
specials today a special at a restaurant
is a dish that isn't usually on the menu
it's something that's special but it's a
special that the show
is offering that day or that week or
that month so sometimes if you don't see
what the specials are you'd ask your
waiter excuse me are there any specials
today could we have the bill please
could we have the bill please this is
how you request that the cheque or the
bill comes to your table could we get
the check please
could we get the bill please you're
asking this to your waiter who will then
bring you the cheque and you can pay 10
words that you can use at a bar let's go
to buy a round the first expression is
to buy a round to buy a round means to
buy a round of drinks essentially a
round of drinks means one drink for
everyone in your group one drink for
everyone in your party by the way the
word party is used to mean group at a
bar or restaurant the number of people
in your party is the number of people in
your group so to buy a round means to
buy a drink for everybody in a sentence
our boss began the party by buying
everyone around in a different sentence
you're buying the next round on the
rocks the next expression is on the
rocks on the rocks is a way to order a
drink when you say on the rocks it means
your drink on ice only so rocks are the
ice in your glass so you can imagine the
ice the pieces of ice in your glass the
ice cubes or an ice ball these are like
rocks
so saying I'd like whiskey for example
on the rocks means just whisky served
over ice
that's what on the rocks mean so in a
sentence I'd like a gin on the rocks
straight up the next expression is
straight up so a straight up drink is
different from an on the rocks drink a
straight up drink is chilled with ice
but it's strained so there's no ice in
the drink but it is it has been chilled
with ice so a straight up drink and
there's nothing else in the glass but it
is a chilled drink in a sentence I'd
like a martini straight up some people
use the word straight or straight up but
they mean
neat which is the next word we're going
to talk about so keep in mind straight
or straight up means chilled that's one
of the key points here so yeah a martini
straight up is a chilled martini neat so
the next expression is neat to order a
drink neat means the drink is not
chilled and there is no ice it's just
it's just the the alcohol it's just the
liquor there's nothing special about it
a neat drink is only the drink that's it
nothing happens to it so in a sentence
I'd like a whiskey neat pint half pint
the next expression is really two
expressions these are words you use when
you order beer they are pint and half
pint depending on the country that you
live in pint can be a different size
they vary by a few milliliters depending
on the country where you live in a half
pint then is roughly half of the piped
size so a half pint and a pint are two
ways two sizes we use to order beer in a
sentence can I have a half pint of this
stout chaser the next expression is
chaser so a chaser is something you use
to follow an alcoholic drink chasers are
often used after shots so shots are
small drinks that are usually kind of
strong and alcohol content and they have
a very strong taste so some people like
to have something after that and they
call it a chaser so the image is that
the the second drink is chasing the
first drink into your body you can think
of it that way the chaser is a
non-alcoholic drink so it could be water
it could be soda it could be something
like that juice maybe mmm so chaser in a
sentence shots of tequila are often
followed with chasers
to be tipsy the next word is to be tipsy
to be tipsy is a way to describe your
feeling when you're drinking so if you
can imagine when you're when you're
standing straight up when you're
standing it's regular you're very like
confident and tall and you don't move
very much but if you feel tipsy this
comes from the verb to tip like this so
something tips
to one side or another think of your
body in this way so we use the word
tipsy the adjective tipsy to describe
this feeling maybe you're not so steady
on your feet you could tip over at any
time that's called being tipsy from
alcohol okay so in a sentence let's see
I'm a little tipsy I need some water
to be drunk the next expression is to be
drunk so we talked about the word tipsy
so tipsy is a little bit like a little
unsteady but drunk is just a mess just
you're just a disaster
you're being noisy you're being loud
it's difficult to control your body or
your friends body whatever so drunk is
usually seen as a negative thing so yeah
so drunk expresses yeah it's it's just
not pretty sometimes so in a sentence
your friend is drunk let's take him home
to call it a night the next expression
is to call it a night
to call it a night means to decide to
finish at the bar to go home you're
ready to be done so here I'm going to
call it I'm going to say this is tonight
tonight is finished mmm
so in a sentence it's been a long
evening I'm gonna call it a night
I mean I'm going to go home I'm done
it's a casual expression hangover and
then one more that you can use maybe the
day after you visit a bar is hangover so
a hangover is a noun
hangover is the word we use to describe
the feelings after drinking too much so
maybe you feel sick to your stomach you
have a headache
your body is sore there are a number of
different feelings you might have when
you feel hung over to be hungover is
another way to say it but when you have
a hangover it usually doesn't feel very
good in a sentence I have a hangover
today I'm not going drinking tonight
about the top 25 english phrases so
let's get started the first phrase is
hello hello of course is used as a
greeting you can greet your friends you
can greet your co-workers your family
with this phrase just by
saying hello hey hi what's up hello so
yo pretty much anytime of day you can
use hello hello the next phrase is good
morning good morning is used as a
greeting in the morning you can kind of
feel when morning ends for you good
morning is nice and polite or even just
morning with your close friends or close
co-workers the next phrase is good night
good night is fine we don't use this to
greet other people we use it when we're
saying good bye to other people at night
family members particularly mothers and
fathers to say good night to their
children before they put them to bed you
can say it to your friend and a text
message or in an email if you've been
talking for a while good night so the
next word to talk about is goodbye use
it when you say goodbye to your friends
when you leave your friends good bye bye
of course take care have a nice day
peace out that's another way to say
goodbye okay the next phrase is I'm plus
your name of course this is a way to
introduce yourself you can use I'm in my
case Alicia I'm Alicia - introduce
yourself in any situation new friend I'm
Alicia
okay the next phrase is what's your name
what's your name is used to ask someone
else what their name is so what is your
name sounds a bit try to use what's your
name if you forget someone's name you
can say sorry what's your name or sorry
what's your name again
next phrase is nice to meet you nice to
meet you any time you meet someone new
nice to meet you is fine good to meet
you is a little more casual great to
meet you sounds very excited pleasure to
meet you sounds like maybe a formal
situation or a business context okay the
next phrase is how are you how are you
is Ann it's just a friendly way to check
in with the other person you can use it
with friends your family your co-workers
maybe even your boss to a certain degree
how are ya how you doin the next phrase
is I'm fine thanks and you if you saw
English in three minutes we talked a lot
about this phrase instead of I'm fine
thank you and you say I'm good thanks
how are you just shorten it and make it
a little bit more natural how are you
good how are you great how are you not
so good how are you okay and so on so
when someone says how are you offer I
usually say I'm good this week i bla bla
give some information about what you've
been up to
a hobby something that you did recently
an event something interesting you saw
whatever people want to make that
connection with you and it's a good
chance for you to continue speaking the
next word is please please as a polite
phrase used when you want something from
someone else you can use this as a
response when someone offers you
something like in a restaurant for
example would you like more water would
you like something to drink
oh please the next phrase is thank you
thank you is used to express your
appreciation you can use thank you with
everybody the next phrase is you're
welcome you're welcome when someone says
thank you you can say you're welcome no
biggie
I use no biggie as in no biggie is short
for no big problem the next word is yes
yes of course yes means is any positive
expression someone asks you a question
and the answer is a positive answer you
say yes yep uh-huh yeah we know next I'm
guessing I knew it yep the next word is
no no is a negative response to
something when you have to give a
negative answer so as you can probably
guess the long form of no is negative I
like to use nope it's very very casual
not gonna happen my parents would use
that with me to soften that a little bit
if you want to show a negative response
to something like let's go for dinner
tonight what do you want to do like do
you want to go out not really hmm
no I don't think so hmm to soften it the
next word is okay okay this word comes
from copy editors okay when they had to
check a manuscript they had to label the
manuscript all clear AC but because they
were copy editors and they have a very
very sick sense of humor they thought
they would mark it okay for all clear to
make a joke because o and K do not start
all and clear but it caught on among
everybody in the world homes anyway okay
is used to agree with somebody else well
it can be used actually to express a
positive or kind of a slight negative I
feel transitioning in your conversation
you can say okay now we're going to talk
about blah blah okay the next phrase is
excuse me excuse me it's used to get
someone's attention in English when you
don't know the other person for example
in a store a supermarket
maybe a stranger on the street you need
to ask directions you can use excuse me
you can use excuse me in the supermarket
excuse me can you tell me where the hot
sauce is if you've done something rude
in public you can use excuse me I
personally do not do rude things in
public ever I'm sorry is the next word
we're gonna talk about I'm sorry is used
to apologize when you have made a
mistake or someone you know it's made a
mistake and you're connected to it or
you just feel bad you can use I'm sorry
you made a mistake at work I'm sorry you
forgot to feed your cat I'm sorry sorry
about that you bump someone next to you
oh sorry what time is it is the next
phrase when you need to check what time
it is what time is it when you ask
someone else what time it is maybe you
say this to yourself to check your watch
check your phone check a clock pretty
straightforward phrase there aren't
really any short version so that's an
easy one
hey where is that plus a location so you
can use this for a building or a store
we don't we're not gonna use this where
is the for a place a city name or a
state name or a country name to do that
you would need to remove the but where
is the bank where is the post office you
can use this to ask directions to ask
for help in your house or at work where
is the copy machine where is the file
I need where is the bla bla bla where is
the bathroom is perhaps a very important
question to know the next one is may I
use the restroom may I use the restroom
is a polite and soft expression that you
can use if you need to use the toilet
you need to use the washroom and when
you're at someone's house for the very
first time when you're in a place that
your that is new to you you can ask may
I use the restroom
more casually can I go to the bathroom
to be very polite you could say may I go
to the bathroom the next phrase is I
would like to order something you can
use this at a restaurant probably or in
any situation where you need to place an
order I'd like a pizza I like beer can I
get the check please this will be used
at a restaurant when you've finished
your meal and it's time to go can I get
the check please in a very very casual
situation you can just say check please
that's fine the next phrase is see you
soon see you soon is used with friends
and family members perhaps when you
expect to see them again soon
after saying goodbye to them this is
used at the end of the conversation
you're going separate directions you see
you soon
seeya is also good or just see you to
make it a little more formal you can say
I'll see you again soon make a full
sentence out of it that way the next
phrases see you later see you later is
very similar to see you soon but the
point is would see you later is that
you're probably going to meet that
person again later on in the same day
the last phrase is really really is a
very useful word because you can use it
to show you were interested in a
conversation with upward intonation
really really tell me more or to show
that you're not so interested in the
conversation with downward intonation
really so there are many other words
that you can use similar to really in
this way like seriously or oh oh and so
on so it's a really good practice for
your intonation about ways to say hi
this should be fun let's get started
first is yo this one is a little bit
casual in case you couldn't tell I used
for close friends maybe family members
if you have kind of a silly relationship
with them just quick short easy to do in
a sentence yo how's it going howdy howdy
traditionally associated with cowboy
culture I suppose you should play a
banjo maybe or you've just gotten off a
horse I don't know I use howdy from time
to time howdy howdy howdy howdy didn't
that's my banjo yeah in a sentence you
might say howdy folks
welcome to the barbecue place
next is hay hay is good friendly phrase
you can usually use hay with a wave and
smile look happy if you don't people
might think that you're down in the
dumps people might think you're not in a
very good mood in a sentence hey I heard
you got engaged last week
congratulations something like that it's
usually kind of a cheery happy
expression all right next is what's up
what's up is the long form of sup this
does not literally mean what is above
you right now if you want to be funny
you can say the ceiling or the sky but
that joke gets old really fast and
chances are the person you're talking to
has already heard it before it just
means what are you up to what is going
on with you in a sentence what's up did
you have a good weekend typical response
- what's up is not much
find out some more responses in English
in three minutes we did an episode on
this nothing much how about you that's
pretty good pretty good pretty good
pretty good the next one is long time no
see you can use this one you haven't
seen the other person for a long time
you're at a party or at an event or
whatever any time it's been a long break
you can decide how long long is not the
day before or the week before maybe a
few weeks or a month whatever is unusual
for you in this other person when you
see them you can say hey a long time no
see how have you been 10 words for
talking about beauty and skincare so
let's begin all right
the first word is makeup makeup is all
makeup everything we're going to talk
about almost everything we're going to
talk about later is makeup makeup is
usually used by women but maybe men use
makeup to makeup is usually put on the
face to change the appearance of the
face in some way so in a sentence I use
makeup almost every day
or I wear makeup almost every day use
and wear are both okay the next word is
eyeshadow so eyeshadow is makeup which
goes on top of the eye so the eyelid
this part is called your eyelid I shadow
goes here on top of the eyelid so in a
sentence
what kind of eyeshadow do you use the
next word is eye liner eyeliner so
eyeliner is used to draw a line to draw
lines near the eyes that means it's safe
to use near eyes it depends on the
person in their style but maybe they use
eyeliner to make lines in different ways
on their on their face off near their
near their eyes in a sentence eyeliner
is really difficult to put on okay the
next word is lipstick lipstick there's
also lip gloss - lipstick is kind of the
traditional just like a single color you
apply it just on your lips and it gives
I don't know not sometimes shiny
sometimes a very neutral I don't know
depends on the lipstick lipgloss gives
lips like this very glossy almost like
liquidy appearance so lipstick and lip
Glaus have different effects in a
sentence you have a lot of lipstick the
next expression is foundation foundation
is the makeup product it is applied to
the skin usually of the face so it's
used to make the face seem like all one
color foundation maybe people apply it
with like a spongy thing or with their
hands or a brush something is it a
Beauty Blender is that a thing I think I
don't know I don't know it's a Beauty
Blender a thing I'm not very good at the
Beauty stuff either a foundation is
intended to make your skin color appear
even foundation so it's called
foundation because it's like the base
the foundation for the rest of your
makeup so the foundation is the kind of
the basis so once your skin color is all
correct and the same than the other
parts we can fix the other parts that's
my theory anyway in a sentence there are
a few different types of foundation all
right the next expression is blush blush
is usually applied on your cheeks and
it's like a pink or red color it gives
the appearance of blushing so when we
feel embarrassed or maybe we feel
excited our cheeks might turn red so
blush is makeup which creates that
effect of blushing this is usually a
pink or red color to simulates to make
it look like you're blushing
even if you're not really in a sentence
do you wear blush the next expression is
bronzer bronzer so we talked about blush
which is supposed to give your skin the
appearance of being pink or blushing
bronzer gives skin the appearance of
being more bronze or more tan so you can
apply this maybe in summer and it makes
your skin look a little more tan which
you might like other people also may use
bronzer to create shadows because it
makes the skin a little bit darker in
the places where it's applied so there
are a few different ways to use bronzer
in a sentence bronzer is nice in summer
the next word is face wash face wash
so the
special soap that's for your face
specifically for the face maybe your
face is very sensitive or you have some
trouble spots or I don't know there's a
specific wash you use for your face only
in a sentence a good face wash is
important for clear skin oh the next
word oh the dreaded I have a couple
words here that are maybe problems all
of us deal with the first kind of
problem word on this list is acne acne
is an uncountable noun acne refers to
you usually this is this a problem
happens for like teenagers or people
around that age but adults can also have
acne acne is like imperfections in the
skin sometimes they're itchy or they're
painful red bumps on your skin or maybe
they're not painful but they're just
blotches or a number of different ways
that acne can can be an issue which
we'll talk about in the next word - but
acne is an uncountable noun is just
about that problem skin problem in
general acne bad acne in a sentence I
had acne when I was a teenager so the
next word for today there are two words
here there's pimple and zit these are
both words we use to refer to the
individual parts of acne acne we can say
I have bad acne or maybe my acne is
improving today but acne is maybe the
whole condition of your face like
everything your if their faces situation
each part each one of those little
problem spots we we call that a pimple
or a zit the difference pimple sounds a
little bit smaller usually as it sounds
a bit bigger and maybe maybe more
painful so but either way pimples and
zits are both words we can use to
describe acne so in a sentence I hate
getting pimples 10 words you can use to
talk about hygiene or cleanliness so
let's be in - wash your hands the first
expression is to wash your hands to wash
your hands is with soap and water in the
restroom somewhere so wash your hands
before cooking
wash your hands after using the toilet
for example in a sentence wash your
hands after using the bathroom to shower
the next expression is to shower to
shower or to shower or maybe you prefer
to take a bath
so to shower is usually standing up
though you can do it sitting down
depending on the country you live in I
suppose to shower is that yeah the water
just hits you continuously to take a
bath is you sit in the bathtub you sit
down and you are surrounded by water
that is a bad bounce around by water in
your home on purpose is a bath if it's
not on purpose you should probably call
plumber because that is not a bath that
is an emergency all right
in a sentence I shower every day or I
love taking a bath every once in a while
to brush your teeth the next expression
is to brush your teeth to brush your
teeth so with a toothbrush usually in
the morning maybe at night as well you
brush your teeth you clean your teeth in
a sentence make sure to brush your teeth
in the morning to style your hair the
next expression is to style your hair to
style your hair means to to arrange or
to fix your hair the way you like it
so today I styled my hair like this you
styled your hair like that eyes tomorrow
maybe I'll style my hair in a ponytail I
probably won't maybe you can put your
you can style your hair in a mohawk or
in a faux hawk or in a bouffant bouffant
that's that focus yeah that's a bouffant
all right
so to style your hair in a sentence it
takes a long time to style my hair
that's true my hair is naturally
explosive and so I have to straighten it
before like everything and then as soon
as humidity gets it it goes
it makes that sound - to shave the next
expression is to shave to shave is to
remove hair like if you're a man here
usually to remove the hair here with a
razor with another like a blade of some
kind or maybe you remove body hair hair
on your legs whatever you we use the
verb to shave to shave with a razor in a
sentence shaving is a pain or sure
meaning shaving is troublesome soap or
cleanser the next word is soap or
cleanser so soap is just used to clean
your skin or yeah to clean your face
maybe to clean your hands we do not use
soap for the stuff you use to clean your
teeth soap is used for like body cleaner
or maybe what you use to wash your
clothes so soap or body cleanser in a
sentence I like nice smelling soaps and
cleansers that is true who does not hmm
deodorant
the next word is deodorant deodorant so
deodorant is the product you might put
on your body to prevent unpleasant
smells so usually it goes in this region
so this is called the armpit this region
so arm and then pit so like yeah kind of
this cave ish area in your arm we call
the armpit but it's common to apply
deodorant here you might put it in other
areas on your body but the goal is to
prevent bad smells or to in some cases
just stop sweating completely so this is
deodorant well deodorant actually if I'm
gonna be strict here deodorant is used
to stop unpleasant smells antiperspirant
is used to prevent sweating so purse
print comes from perspire so to perspire
means to sweat ante means not or stop so
an antiperspirant isn't a product to
make you stop sweating hmm so deodorant
is the smell one antiperspirant is the
sweat one
sometimes you can buy a deodorant and
antiperspirant together
great in a sentence wearing deodorant is
important especially in summer mouthwash
the next word is mouthwash mouthwash I
hope is easy to understand it's wash
it's something to clean the inside of
your mouth so you can use this like in
the morning maybe after you brush your
teeth or after lunch maybe to keep your
breath smelling fresh but it usually is
in like a blue or a green or maybe an
orange color and kind of has a minty or
citrusy taste but you put it in your
mouth and kind of swish like I don't
know I can't swish nothing you could
switch it around in your mouth and then
spit it out and that's mouthwash
so you've washed your mouth with this
product in a sentence I like minty
mouthwash toothpaste the next word is
toothpaste so toothpaste we do not say
like tooth soap or tooth cleaner or
whatever we use toothpaste for the
product to clean our teeth the product
we use to brush our teeth is called
tooth paste so in a sentence I need to
buy more toothpaste shampoo and
conditioner the next expression is
shampoo and conditioner so shampoo and
conditioner are commonly used together
in the shower or in the bath maybe
shampoo usually comes first we shampoo
shampoo is soap for your hair really and
then conditioner is a treatment for your
hair conditioner is used to make your
hair feel softer or more moisturized so
often times they are used for shampoo
and then conditioner together as a set
so in a sentence I like trying new
shampoos and conditioners want to speak
real English from your first lesson sign
up for your free lifetime account at
English class 101 calm
gossip let's go oh my god
so the first phrase is oh my god so so
oh my god so is a introductory phrase
you can use to start your topic with
like a surprise factor so you say oh my
god and then so is your transition
phrase so for example oh my god so I
have to tell you about this movie I saw
or oh my god so I saw my neighbor in the
shopping mall this morning or oh my god
so did you see my new dog it's kind of a
weird one usually it's about a person
not about a dog but who knows you won't
believe what happened to me the other
day the next expression is you won't
day you won't believe what happened to
me the other day meaning something
happened to you and you think it's going
to be a surprise to the person listening
to you you won't believe what happened
to me the other day so it's a very fast
phrase because it sounds like you want
to share very quickly like you won't
believe what happened to me you can drop
the other day if you want or you said
you can say you won't believe what
happened to me this morning you won't
believe what happened to me last night
you won't believe it happened to me this
weekend you won't believe what happened
to me over my winter vacation so that
you won't believe what happened to me
gets very very quick and short so
examples you won't believe what happened
to me the other day
I've ran into my ex-boss or you won't
believe what happened to me the other
day I tripped and fell down a flight of
stairs or you won't believe what
happened to me the other day I got a new
parrot
sure I don't know maybe one of you can
use that guess what the next phrase is
very short the next phrase is like an
exclamation so an excited statement and
a question guess what guess what so
guess what is inviting the listener to
guess what happened to you yes what the
full question would be guess what
happened or guess what happened to me
but we only say guess what so guess what
and sometimes the listener guesses and
sometimes the listener just says what
usually the listener just says what ask
so meaning you should continue the story
so if you say guess what I quit my job
or guess what I saw my best friend with
a new guy I haven't seen before
another example guess what I got a new
car something like that so some kind of
shocking like difficult to guess
situation I haven't told you about this
yet the next expression is I haven't
told you about this yet I haven't told
you about this yet so have not becomes
haven't I haven't told you about this
yet so maybe you've told you have told
other people but this specific person
maybe you have not told that person your
news or some information yet but this
yet implies you are planning to or you
want to tell them this so it's it's kind
of creates a little suspense I haven't
told you about this yet so we could use
this like I haven't told you about this
yet I'm going to France next summer or I
haven't told you about this yet but I
broke up with my boyfriend last night or
I haven't told you about this yet but
I'm throwing a big party for my coworker
this weekend can you come other examples
I haven't told you about this yet I saw
my boss out for dinner with someone
who's not his wife Oh oh my god that's
not true I haven't told you about this
yet I heard
that the company is gonna go bankrupt Oh
also not true okay so those are some
pretty juicy juicy gossip that's an
expression we use we say juicy gossip is
something that's like really really
interesting gossip or a really
interesting story about people we say
juicy gossip for that have you heard
about the next expression is have you
heard about blah blah blah have you
heard about can be followed with a noun
phrase have you heard about a person you
can use a person or have you heard about
a situation you can use both you can use
an object - so have you heard about the
new iPhone or have you heard about the
new office policies you can use that for
pretty much anything you want to inform
your listener about so have you heard
about is usually said very quickly have
you heard about so the U becomes
shortened - yeah have you heard about
have you heard about local blah
so have you heard about the new
secretary have you heard about our new
boss sir have you heard about my
co-worker quitting his job have you
heard about the neighbors above us
they're moving so you can use people
here for a gossip expressions or you can
use objects in this expression just to
introduce something new very useful
phrase have you heard about my mum sorry
mom I don't know why you came into that
one okay so the other day the next
expression is kind of like the beginning
to a story so maybe this can be for
gossip maybe it can just be like a story
something that interesting or maybe
boring that happened to you the
expression is so the other day so the
other day so the other day the other day
here means not today
some other day which day it doesn't
really matter it's not really important
but we say the other day some day in the
past this expression is used for so we
can say so the other day I was sitting
at my desk in the office when my manager
came and asked if he could speak to me
done
or so the other day I was shopping and I
ran into my ex-boyfriend or so the other
day I was renting a car and the former
President of the United States came into
the car rental shop what all right so
the other day just some day in the past
so I was talking with and the next one
you can use maybe for gossip sometimes
but also you can use for making plans
it's so I was talking with someone and
blah blah blah so I was talking with
someone means you were having a
conversation at another time with a
person and you want to kind of report
information or share something from that
conversation with the person listening
now so I might say so I was talking with
Risa and I think that we should plan a
party for this weekend what do you think
so I was talking with my team about this
and I think that we should make some
changes so that's a very kind of
everyday work situation use of this
phrase but you can also use it for
gossip like so I was talking to my best
friend and I think I'm gonna move or I
was talking to my parents and I think
it's best if we break up oh so it can be
for plans it can be for gossip it can be
for just any conversation plus a report
what's up with the next expression is
kind of a little like mysterious then
the expression is what's up with blah
blah blah
usually what's up with person for gossip
meaning there's like the nuance here is
there some problem where it seems like
something's wrong with this person
they're unhappy they're sad they're
angry some kind of negative emotion we
use this so it's like what's up with
Stevens I haven't heard from him lately
what's up with your brother he seems
really upset or what's up with your
neighbor why is he so noisy or what's up
with your boss he's so strict so it
sounds like there's some problem we you
surely use this intonation what's up
with what's up with no to introduce
somebody who has a problem we don't say
what's up it's not that it's not that
sort of hello um expression it's a it's
an expression for a problem you can also
use a noun phrase that is not a person
here like what's up with this new office
policy or what's up with this new rule
at work or what's up with this new item
on the menu at this restaurant it's
super weird so what's up with blah blah
blah has sort of a negative nuance you
can use it for people to talk about
strange behavior what's up with you have
you heard from lately the next
expression is have you heard from blah
blah blah lately have you heard from
person lately have you heard from
steven's lately I haven't seen him have
you heard from your mom lately have you
heard from your dad lately have you
heard from your brother lately have you
heard from your landlord lately I don't
know why you hear from your landlord but
have you heard from someone lately there
is sort of enix like a little bit of an
expectation that you are in contact with
the person involved in this sentence
like you have some relationship maybe
it's a family relationship romantic
relationship professional relationship
there's some relationship with this
person and lately is like have you heard
from them recently lately in the last
few days in the last few weeks so you
can use this if for example you are
looking for someone or you're worried
about someone you can use this here you
can also use it just just to check in
about some other person without asking
that person directly so like if I want
to ask about I'm using Risa in my
example Risa is our Japanese Channel
host if I want to ask about how Risa is
but I don't want to ask Risa I know
maybe she's busy or I don't know for
some reason I difficult to talk to her I
can ask like a co-worker I'm gonna say
hey have you heard from recently at
least it seems she's really busy or have
you heard from so-and-so lately it seems
they're busy so if I want to ask about
another person but I don't want to
bother this person or the
something makes it difficult I can use
have you heard from blah blah blah
recently or lately
to ask about them very useful phrase I
have to tell you about
next expression ah the next expression
is I have to tell you about bah-bah-bah
I have to tell you so have to becomes
hafta I have to tell you about it has a
nice hmmm-hmmm sound I have to tell you
about Papa bah or I have to tell you
about something so I have to tell you
about my weekend I have to tell you
about Stevens I have to tell you about
my mom I had to tell you about my
boyfriend
I should tell you about my girlfriend
whatever it is some person used at the
end of this sentence creates a nuance
like there's exciting news about that
person or I have to tell you about this
thing that happened you can use a
situation at the end of the sentence -
but you're using I have to at the
beginning of this sentence so that
sounds like it's really important like I
feel it's so important it's my
responsibility to tell you because this
is so exciting
of course you can use this in more
boring situations as well like I have to
tell you about the new office policy you
can use it in that way with a very flat
intonation but for gossip purposes use I
have to tell you about bah-bah-bah
that sounds really good so what do you
have to tell somebody about I have to
tell you about this new idea I have for
a business or I have to tell you about
what happened to me last night okay so
there are these really exciting ways
that we can introduce things that
happened or that we can talk about
people or whatever okay 10 words for
talking about space planet the first
word is planet planet so planets are
those really really big things that we
have in our solar system now there are
officially eight because Pluto is no
longer considered a planet in my example
sentence Pluto used to be considered a
planet star the next word is star star
so stars are those very very bright
objects that you can see in the sky
sometimes at night that's the closest
star to us is the Sun the Sun is a star
and we can see a lot of other stars if
we look up into the night sky sometimes
in a sentence it's hard to see stars
from big cities solar system the next
expression is solar system solar system
so solar system
our case here on planet earth refers to
the system of planets and objects which
are near our star so our solar system
now there are eight planets in our solar
system used to be nine planets sorry
again in Pluto eight planets in our
solar system and then we can talk about
other objects which maybe enter our
solar system like like comets for
example or a meteor or some other events
might happen in space within our solar
system so our solar system is the area
surrounding our Sun and our planets that
we know of in a sentence
mercury is part of our solar system
comet the next expression is comet a
comet is actually an icy body that is
slightly melting and then releasing
gases so that's what produces that look
a comet okay in a sentence comets are
really cool meteor alright so yes the
next word is meteor or meteor or just
meteor
so essentially meteors are different
from comets because comets are made of
ice meteors however are made of rock so
these are two different kinds of objects
that can that move around in space in a
sentence lots of meteors burn up before
they pass through the atmosphere
meteorite the next word is meteor right
meteor right so this is an important
distinction that many people don't know
about actually if this tries to be crazy
too so a meteor is the is the space
rockets in space or it's in the
atmosphere a meteor right however is the
rock if if the meteor makes it if the
meteor can pass through the Earth's
atmosphere and fall to the surface of
the earth that rock then is called a
meteor right so in space in the
atmosphere it's a meteor when it falls
to earth it is a meteorite that becomes
a meteorite when it hits the earth so
fun facts okay that's the difference
between the two in a sentence have you
ever seen a meteorite supernova
supernova supernova so the explosion of
a star is a huge event a supernova is
the name of it so the star explodes
and that's what we call it it's called a
supernova a star explosion in a sentence
supernovas must be incredible things
black hole all right the next expression
is black hole black hole black holes are
the subject of a lot of study they have
intense gravitational pull so meaning
they have very strong gravity black
holes will pull other objects into them
it is said that like time stops in a
black hole or in like if you get too
close to a black hole if you get too
close to the event horizon of a black
hole you yourself will be pulled into
that hole too it's pretty crazy
so like the event horizon is the point
at which there's no there's no turning
back from like you can't you can't
escape essentially the gravitational
pull of a black hole once you're within
the event horizon of that space it's
like crazy all this kind of stuff is so
interesting so in a sentence black holes
are mysterious galaxies okay
all right so the next word is galaxies
galaxies before we talked about the
expression solar system so solar system
is kind of our region of space the
region we're familiar with but the next
step up so if you think of the solar
system is kind of your neighborhood a
little bit you could think of maybe the
galaxy is like your city or your country
maybe it's sort of the next step out so
a galaxy is made up of lots and lots of
stars maybe other planets other solar
system many other solar systems in one
galaxy so I think yeah we belong to the
Milky Way galaxy I believe in a sentence
our galaxy is made of lots of different
stars and planets earth the next
expression is earth earth earth is our
planet Earth is the planet we live on
earth is habitable meaning humans can
live here this word I included it in
this vocabulary list because it is a
very good word to practice your
pronunciation it is the word earth earth
that are and the th sound can be
difficult to pronounce together earth
earth so this is a great word to use to
practice your pronunciation earth so in
a sentence our
it is called earth 10 words for talking
about sleep let's go to wake up the
first word is to wake up to wake up is
to open your eyes probably in your bed
or the place where you are sleeping to
wake up is to to become conscious to
become awake every day you wake up
presumably hopefully in a sentence I
woke up three times last night to get up
to get out of bed all right the next
word is to get up or to get out of bed
so that means to physically move your
body from your bed out of bed to stand
up from your bed to get out of your bed
we say to get up or to get out of bed in
a sentence I got up at 8 o'clock this
morning to snooze the next word is to
snooze so we have to snooze and alarm
and also to snooze
so to snooze means to take a short sleep
to have a short sleeping time or to
snooze and alarm is when your alarm goes
off in the morning you have a button
most alarm clocks have some button you
can press so the alarm will turn on
again in like you know 5 or 10 minutes
or something so to snooze an alarm is to
like to ask your alarm to wake you up
again a few minutes later that's to
snooze so we have to snooze an alarm and
to snooze meaning like a short light
sleep in a sentence
I always snooze my alarm at least once
that is usually true to oversleep the
next word is to oversleep to oversleep
means to sleep too much or to sleep late
actually no it doesn't mean to sleep
late to sleep late means just to sleep
until a late time in the day oversleep
means sleeping beyond the time you
wanted to get up so for example if my
alarm is set for 8 o'clock but I wake up
at
o'clock I overslept I slept beyond my
wake-up time so we can use oversleep to
talk about times when you sleep
too much you sleep more than your body
needs you to so maybe your body needs
depending on the person like six to nine
hours or so but if you sleep like 14
hours we can say that's over sleeping
you're sleeping too much hmm that's the
nuance here in a sentence I overslept on
my first day of work
nap the next word is nap nap is a short
sleep so a nap is maybe 30 minutes one
hour just a short sleep a short rest so
a lot of people will take a nap in the
afternoon for example or maybe children
actually take naps for example in
preschool or when they're very very
young they have a an afternoon nap a
short sleep like hmm yeah just a like an
hour or so I imagine in a sentence I
love naps actually I do like naps I
don't like naps because when I take a
nap it becomes asleep it's always like I
wake up four hours later and I'm like
okay well I've destroyed my sleep
schedule dream the next word is dream
dreams so dreams are those those visions
those images you see those experiences
it seems like you have when you are
asleep in a sentence I always have weird
dreams nightmare so the next word is
nightmare nightmare is a word which
means bad dream or scary dream negative
dream so children maybe have nightmares
a lot they wake up crying or they're
really upset by nightmares monsters
terrifying things happening and so on in
a sentence do you ever have nightmares
to go to bed the next word is to go to
bed so before we talked about to get up
or to get out of bed this is the
opposite to go to bed means to get in
your bed - to try to go to sleep to go
to bed in a sentence I usually go to bed
fairly late
to hit the hay to hit the sack the next
expression is kind of a I don't know a
slang expression we have to hit the hay
and to hit the sack
these both mean to go to bed they both
mean to try to fall asleep but we just
use them in more casual situations the
image here of hit the hay is with your
body hitting hay like laying down in hay
I believe historically because hay was
used to stuff things that people slept
on so that's why we have this expression
to hit the hay with your body
same thing for to hit the sack so a sack
full of something soft to sleep on is
where this expression comes from in a
sentence I think I'm gonna hit the hay
to fall asleep the next expression it is
to fall asleep to fall asleep you're in
bed and you finally you lose
consciousness you you stop being aware
you are asleep in that moment we say you
fall asleep in a sentence it takes me a
long time to fall asleep
alright wanna speak real English from
your first lesson sign up for your free
lifetime account at English class 101
calm
top ten must know prepositions and
conjunctions for English learners let's
get started - - I threw the ball to my
dad - is sort of directional it it's
saying that it's going towards something
I wrote a letter to my mother I went to
the mall I went to the park my mom asked
me to go to the store to buy some bread
- a destination to a person from from
from is the opposite of - from implies
where it's coming from the place of
origin so if I'm going to the mall I'm
coming from my house this letter is from
my daughter from how long does it take
you to get from your house to your job -
and from they go together with with with
it means together with something I am at
the movies with my friend I went out to
eat with my friends I go shopping with
my boyfriend with means you are together
with something I like to have grilled
cheese with tomatoes on it I'm here with
my book @ @ @ is a very short word I
always go to bed at 11 o'clock if I'm
lucky I usually go to bed at around 1:00
in the morning unfortunately you get
very little sleep at specifies a time or
a place let's go to the movies at 2:00
in the afternoon I'm at home right now
where are you we decided to meet at the
beach
it's a pinpoint of time or location in
in in means you are inside of something
or in the middle of something
it means being immersed in something I
am in bed right now the cat is in the
box the child is in the tree the plane
is in the sky I graduated school in 2019
in gone on I left the book on my desk on
means on top of I like ketchup on my
fries so that means my french fries are
here and I like to put ketchup on them
the man is on the roof the car is on the
street the motorcycle is on my nerves
but but I think I remember her name but
I'm not sure but is a way to add a
negative to a sentence so for example I
really love eating cake but I don't eat
it often because it's not healthy I'd
love to go to the movies with you but I
have too much work to do I really like
you but I don't want to date you and and
and is a very common word you will hear
all the time it's a way of adding on a
new subject or thing to your sentence I
love candy and pizza I'm hungry and I'm
tired my friend moved to Spain and I
moved to Canada I love playing outside
and I love being inside and is a way to
add on a new subject or thing to what
you're talking about so so I have a
toothache so I went to the dentist so is
a way of adding an example another way
to say because of this I did this you
say something and then you add so and
then what follows is the effect so
there's the cause so the effect
so I was feeling very hungry so I had
some pizza this video is going to be
Pizza themed everyone apparently I was
really tired so I took a nap I was in
the mood for some adventure so I got on
an airplane and flew to Mexico that
sounds nice or-or-or is a way of
presenting a choice so for example you
can either have pizza or you can have
candy I don't know if I should go to the
movies or if I should go to the mall
which color do you like better red or
green
it presents differences of choice
today's video is on words Americans
overuse I haven't seen these words yet
but apparently it's going to be a series
of words that we as Americans I'm
American we overuse we use too often so
let's start oh the first word is
definitely definitely is definitely a
word that Americans overuse we use it to
put emphasis at the end of a phrase to
put emphasis the end of a sentence as in
oh that party last week was so great
yeah definitely or to agree with
somebody like that uh Oh God
literally uh just in the last few days
I've seen the word literally so many
times on the internet and used in just
such stupid ways the word literally
means actually or truly something this
is literally the best hamburger I've
ever eaten so literally meaning truly or
actually would mean that in that
person's entire life that is the best
hamburger they've ever eaten however it
gets misused a lot in sentences like
George Bush was literally supporting the
war in Iraq or something like that
taking a phrase like that literally
would have to mean that you know the
president former president would be you
know physically supporting a war with
his body onward onward hilarious
hilarious is the next word I like to use
the word hilarious when something is
actually funny hilarious of course means
something that is really funny super
funny it
to step above funny maybe two steps
three steps I don't know however people
like to use this word in place of
laughter so for example friends are
talking and instead of just laughing the
friend will say that's hilarious but
well if it's so hilarious just laugh oh
this must be the last one because this
is the worst one this word is like I've
probably said it several times already
today for the for the purposes of this
video the word like is used as a filler
word so it's the same as something such
as um or uh or hmm for example we use
like as a filler word when we're trying
to think of something you it's not
uncommon to hear the word repeated like
three four or five times in a row when
someone is thinking they'll say oh you
know that party that I went to like like
like like do you know who was there it
just invades your speech sometimes when
you're trying to think of something and
no other filler words come out but the
word like does ah this wasn't the last
word there is another one seriously yeah
seriously it's used oh it's it's good
for any time you receive bad news well
not from your boss it's a really casual
word but if you hear something like your
friend lost their job and you can
sympathize with them or maybe empathize
with them by saying seriously oh that's
too bad or Oh tell me like all your
problems oh my god oh just use like oh
good well I hate myself generic
trademarks oh oh these are all examples
of brands that wear the name of the
brand has become synonymous with
whatever the brand product itself is
this is gonna be fun
Jacuzzi oh really a Jacuzzi is a brand I
didn't know that see okay Jacuzzi is a
hot tub essentially it's just it's a
it's a type of hot tub but so many
people have come to know that Jacuzzi
equals hot tub that Jacuzzi now just
means hot tub even though it's the name
of the brand so you might say hey come
over to my house this weekend we're all
going to have a
no you might say oh I just bought a new
jacuzzi do you want to come in
no that's creepy - mm-hmm I'm thinking
about buying a jacuzzi do you have any
recommendations hmm
next chapstick you might use chapstick I
use chapstick chapstick is just a brand
of lip balm so whenever your lips feel
dry or when they feel chapped you put
chapstick on your lips in a sentence you
might say I carry my chapstick with me
everywhere I love it
Kleenex Kleenex is another great example
of a brand that now equals a product oh
here's Kleenex is this Ashlee Kleenex no
this is a school can you see it no this
is actually this is not Kleenex but we'd
probably refer to this as Kleenex yeah
tissue these are just they're just
tissues it's not even made by I made by
Kleenex can you pass me a Kleenex
next is post-its Oh post-its are very
useful they're just a small notepad
here's another one there's some notes
written on it already this is a small
one also not made by post-it but it's
the same it's the same sort of thing
it's just a piece of paper that has a
sticky back and you can stick it to
things but post-its now people will ask
for a post-it instead of just a sticky
back note paper well I guess I guess
posted is an easier thing to say what
else what you call it if not a post-it
sticky paper
our glue note
I'm waiting for you entrepreneurs next
is band-aids this was the first one that
I thought of actually when I saw this
topic band-aids when you get hurts when
you get a paper cut it's that little
piece of kind of tape II
bandage that you peel stuff off of and
then you stick on whenever you've just
hurt but that thing is just called a
bandage right it's a sticky bandage
there are a lot of sticky things it's
most of the time I think when you get a
paper cut or something at work or at
school or whatever they'll say oh my
gosh do you need a band-aid his words
that vary by region Creek I say Creek
you might hear the word Creek Creek and
the word Creek means a small river
essentially there's a Creek in my
backyard
for example sure the next word is coyote
I say coyote how do other people say
this word kite coyote oh yeah coyote I
don't say that coyote is kind of a
doglike animal it's a wild animal about
the size of a dog with a howl at night
we had them in Oregon where I'm from I
definitely heard them at my house last
night I heard the Coyotes out in my
pasture okay the next word is root ro
ute root is how I say it you might also
hear the word pronounced route root ro
ute means the way through a city or a
town or some kind of path in other words
ro ot which this word sounds like is the
system that's at the bottom of a plant
that plant uses to get nutrients you
know with the little hairy fibers I'm so
good at explaining plant biology oh I
know a good route to get from school to
the park later let's take that on our
bicycles that was oddly specific the
next word is apricot or you might hear
apricot as well it's a fruit so you
might say hey did you bring any apricots
to the picket ticket to the big
apricots no I pick it on the other hand
is a word that means protest there's a
freebie in there for example you might
say hey I really like those apricots you
brought me the other day they were
delicious
okay the next ooh the next word is
caramel I say I think I say caramel
oh this is making me doubt myself
there's caramel and there's caramel they
both refer to sugary sweet substance
that's often a type of candy or often
inside a type of candy it's really
really delicious so you might say oh my
favorite kind of candy is caramel or my
favorite kind of candy is caramel just
depends on where you're from apparently
in the East the East Coast they say
caramel on the west coast it seems we
say
caramel that sounds about right to me
hmm you can choose faces that aren't
cool anymore whoo-hoo
I probably say a whole lot of these
phrases so I'm about to embarrass myself
the first phrase is sweet Oh sweets not
cool anymore
sweet means cool sweet means something
that's good you might say oh man that's
skateboard trick you just did was sweet
groovy I still say groovy groovy means
cool guru means good it was used in the
seventies when you know funky groovy
music was popular in a sentence like oh
hey those are some groovy moves on the
kids I don't know we can use that going
steady going steady is kind of an
old-fashioned phrase as well going
steady just means you're dating someone
who is dating someone else like me and
Tricia are going steady what just means
you're dating you're a couple not oh
this is this word is actually what the
entire holiday of April Fool's Day is
based around that's a lie
particularly I would say for junior high
school students this phrase is um very
popular they might say something like
hey Steve thinks you're cute not so in
other words it's often used as an insult
duh duh duh is used when someone says
something really stupid or something
really obvious so if you say something
like oh hey it's raining the other
person who can also maybe look out the
window you're both sitting in front of
might say duh because you've just
indicated something very very obvious
you
also used to make fun of yourself when
you do or say something really stupid as
soon as you realize this you can go ah
duh yeah
intermediate latin phrases that's gonna
be fun
bonafide it sounds like an american
thing like like oui oui bastardized that
word of it
bona fide then means something that's
genuine or something that's truly
representative of something else so if
someone says he's a bona fide gentleman
for example it means he's truly a
gentleman I don't hear this word very
often at least among people I spent time
with perhaps you might hear it
especially in an old movie I think vice
versa vice versa means basically it just
means to switch positions of something
so you might say oh I could come to your
house and then we could go no this is a
terrible example I can go to your house
or vice versa
meaning you come to my house so saying
vice versa it leaves the listener to
fill in the opposite of whatever else
you're saying yeah that's actually kind
of a useful phrase that's still used
quite a lot I hear a lot in kind of
business English OMA mater alma mater
alma mater alma mater just refers to the
college that you graduated from so
whatever it is whatever your university
is you could be from you know Harvard
University you would say Oh Harvard is
my alma mater that's it
carpe diem carpe diem carpe diem means
seize the day so it's a kind of a
motivating phrase you can say it maybe
when you leave the house for work for
example if you're feeling like you need
an extra bit of motivation you might say
yeah carpe diem to yourself status quo
status quo refers to the norm or
whatever is the regular in society for
example right now let's see what's this
what's a status quo politics that want a
beer ain't anybody so maybe in one place
the status quo might be to eat vegan
maybe oh it's you know eating vegan is
the status quo we're going to look at
some common English idioms let's begin
the first word or phrase rather is about
- about - means you're going to start
something you're going to begin doing
something for example I'm about to start
explaining this idiom to you hey hey
okay the next word or phrase idiom the
next idiom is by the way the word here
they've used is incidentally it's a way
to transition to another topic that's
related to what you're talking about for
example this week I'm going to a party
by the way did you hear about the party
happening next week so there's somewhat
related mm-hmm okay
the next idiom is in a way in a way this
is kind of in a way it was a good thing
that the burrito shop was closed because
otherwise I would have eaten way too
much and you can use this to show that
there may be two sides to a situation
maybe some things are negative maybe
some things are positive next is on the
other hand I hear this a lot on the
other hand is a way of just saying
however or to share two different sides
to a story for example I think my
coworker is really irritating on the
other hand at parties he's really funny
so you can show two maybe different
sides to a point with this phrase next
is a matter of fact as a matter of fact
as an idiom this is a long way to just
say actually or really it's a little bit
more formal sounding so you might use it
in a business meeting for example
everybody at the business meeting might
feel a little bit unsure about the
previous month sales and you can begin
your presentation by saying something
like I know everybody was a little bit
unsure about last week's or last month's
sales performance but as a matter of
fact things improved wanna speak real
English from your first lesson sign up
for your free lifetime account at
English class 101.com want to finally
start speaking in your target language
in this guide you'll discover the top 7
ways to practice speaking on your own
with our lessons let's begin number one
shadowing shadowing is a proven learning
technique where all you do is repeat
what you hear in order to practice
speaking
so access any audio or video lesson on
the site and press the play button to
start then as you listen or watch just
repeat the conversations or even easier
read along out loud with the dialogue
section the script is right there in
front of you with our lessons you can
master entire conversations just like
number two read out loud I just
mentioned it but reading out loud is
another powerful tactic and deserves its
own mention with every lesson you get
written transcripts and translations so
as you play the lesson read the dialogue
out loud as you hear it why by reading
out loud you're also practicing your
speaking skills you can do this with the
lesson notes the lesson transcript or
the dialogue tool with the dialogue tool
you can listen to each line again and
again and repeat out loud until you
master them all number three speed up
your reading to speed up your speaking
being able to speak without thinking is
a sign of language mastery if you're
talking to a native and can respond
quickly they'll assume that you're
fairly fluent how can you do this when
you read out loud try increasing your
speed a little bit every time so start
by reading with a dialogue tool if
you're like most learners you'll read
the first line slowly that's because
you're still getting used to the words
which is okay reread it on your second
try
you know most of the words and you'll
read a little faster reread it again on
your third try you'll be even faster at
a native speaker speed and being able to
read these phrases out loud and fast
will help you speak fast number four
record and compare yourself with native
speakers in order to sound like a native
speaker
you must imitate native speakers so
here's how access the voice recorder
which is in the dialog study tool in
every lesson click on the microphone
icon listen to the native speakers audio
and then record yourself you can then
compare the two recordings side-by-side
and practice and try again and again
until you perfect your pronunciation
number five
get feedback from our Premium Plus
teacher if you're learning by yourself
and don't have access to real teachers
then you can always get feedback from
our Premium Plus teachers
with my teacher tool you can record
yourself speaking and send the audio
file to the teacher they'll review it
and tell you what to improve and how
that's it number six level up your
speaking with Premium Plus assignments
with Premium Plus you can also get
assignments that cover reading writing
listening and even speaking from your
teacher these assignments can be
tailored to your goals and needs you get
a new one every week or any time you're
ready for a new one number seven get
even more lessons in the lesson library
if you want even more lessons on
speaking and conversations visit our
lesson library and under category choose
conversation you'll get all of the
pathways and lessons that are focused on
speaking how to curse like an English
native speaker piss a slang term for
urine for example don't piss your pants
you can say this when you're really
scared or anxious for example if you're
about to go on stage to make a speech or
perform someone can say don't piss your
pants you can do it pissed off to be
really angry when I'm angry I can say
hey I'm really pissed off at you right
now
why did you do that for loser used to
describe an uncool person in high school
my friends and I would use this a lot
and we would say hey loser how's it
going idiot used to install people by
saying they're not intelligent of all
the mean things that you can say this is
on the lighter side but people still use
it shoot this is used to show
disappointment or frustration without
using a stronger curse word shoot I
spilled my coffee shut up
you can use this when you want them to
be quiet or there's something surprising
that you just heard you can say shut up
no way ticked off to be really angry
you can say this with pissed-off so this
is actually an older term not many
people use this as much anymore because
most people actually just use pissed-off
fool this is similar to saying someone
is like a clown you can say you're
acting like a fool right now jerk this
is a light insult used to describe
someone who is mean for example if
there's someone bullying another person
that person is being a jerk
whip this means someone who isn't strong
there is a movie out right now called
Diary of a Wimpy Kid have you seen it
have you not I haven't yet ten ways to
say hello in English good morning good
morning is the first thing you say to
someone when you see them in the morning
good morning sir would you like a cup of
coffee
good morning could I please get some
orange juice good morning I'm still
tired from the night before hello hello
is the most common greeting you'll hear
that and hi hello is a polite nice way
to greet someone when you see them hello
everyone says it you cannot go wrong
saying hello hello can be used at any
time of the day no matter whether it's
morning or at night or at 4:00 a.m. when
you see someone you can say hello and it
will still be appropriate long time no
see long time no see it's not
necessarily grammatically correct but
it's a saying that we have hey long time
no see what it means is that you haven't
seen that person in a long time so it
literally means long time no see long
time no see is something you say to
someone when you haven't seen them in a
while
hey John long time no see how are the
wife and kids how have you been
Hey how have you been I haven't seen you
in a long time
how have you been is asking someone how
they're doing and how they've been for
the past however long if you haven't
seen them in a while you might say hey
long time no see
how have you been how have you been
that's past tense it implies that you
haven't seen them in a while and you
want to hear about how they are and how
they've been for all of that time that
you haven't seen them hey long time no
see how have you been
how are you how are you means how are
you doing how are you feeling how is
everything it's a standard thing that
you might say to anyone even if you've
seen them the day before you might see
them today I'd say hey how are you how's
it going hey how's it going how's it
going is a more informal way to say how
are you so how are you and how's it
going they mean the same thing it's
asking how you're doing how you are
feeling is everything okay with you
what's up what's up is another way of
saying hey how is it going but this one
is even more informal so you might say
this to friends hey what's up and
they'll say nothing just living my life
you know day in and day out hey what's
up hey what's up good afternoon good
afternoon how are you would you like
some lunch good afternoon is a polite
way to greet someone in the afternoon so
if you run into your boss you might say
good afternoon it's very nice it's
polite not a lot of people say it to
their friends but it's it's a polite way
to greet someone good evening good
evening is a nice way to greet someone
in the evening time you can only use
this phrase in the evening because it's
wishing someone a good evening
it's saying hello at a certain time
des good evening would you like some
dinner good evening
have you eaten yet all of my examples
involve food it seems it's nice to meet
you it's nice to meet you
this is something that's very common to
say the first time that you meet someone
you might shake their hand and say hi
it's nice to meet you my name is
Brigitte
my name is it's telling that person that
you are happy to be meeting them it's a
pleasure to meet them hi it's nice to
meet you hi everyone
I'm Gabriela how are your English
listening skills in this video you'll
have a chance to test them out with a
quiz first you'll see an image and here
a question next comes a short dialogue
listen carefully and see if you can
answer correctly we'll show you the
answer at the end are you ready
a woman is asking a store clerk
something at a bookstore which book does
the woman want to see excuse me I'd like
to take a look at a book on that shelf
which book would you like the one about
cars one moment please
this one yep that's right
here you go
which book does the woman want to see
a woman is asking a store clerk
something at a bookstore which book does
the woman want to see excuse me I'd like
to take a look at a book on that shelf
which book would you like the one about
cars one moment please
this one yep that's right here you go
a man and a woman are looking over a
menu at a restaurant what's the man
going to order what are you going to
order the pizza looks delicious I think
I'll go with that I had pizza yesterday
so okay then what about the hamburger
sounds good
I'll go with that
what's the man going to order
a man and a woman are looking over a
menu at a restaurant what's the man
going to order what are you going to
order the pizza looks delicious I think
I'll go with that I had pizza yesterday
so okay then what about the hamburger
sounds good
I'll go with that
a man is calling the doctor's office
what time does he need to be at the
doctor's office bye hello how can I help
you what time do you close today
we close at 6 o'clock but please come in
before 5:30 okay thank you
what time does he need to be at the
doctor's office by
a man is calling the doctor's office
what time does he need to be at the
doctor's office bye hello how can I help
you what time do you close today
we close at 6 o'clock but please come in
before 5:30 okay thank you
a boy is reading from his journal what
was the first thing the boy did today
the weather was great today I went
swimming this afternoon at the pool and
I went to a movie in the evening I also
studied all morning today wasn't bad
what was the first thing the boy did
today
a boy is reading from his journal what
was the first thing the boy did today
the weather was great today I went
swimming this afternoon at the pool and
I went to a movie in the evening I also
studied all morning today wasn't bad
a woman and a man are looking at a
photograph which photo are they looking
at this is a photo of the soccer team
your son is on isn't it which one is
your son this one oh he's the tallest
one yep he's even taller than the coach
which photo are they looking at
a woman and a man are looking at a
photograph which photo are they looking
at this is a photo of the soccer team
your son is on isn't it which one is
your son this one oh he's the tallest
one yep he's even taller than the coach
did you get it right I hope you learned
something from this quiz let us know if
you have any questions see you next time
[Music]